PAUL: Okay, so today we'll be starting with the next part.
PAUL: Yeah, so let's start with a quick recap, so…
PAUL: The points do things that were mentioned, okay? I have taken that into account.
PAUL: And let me know the audio is fine.
PAUL: Yes, everyone.
PAUL: Alright, so let's go to…
PAUL: I think this is my desktop. Alright.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so the first thing with respect to the recap of the previous class, so in the last class, if you remember. Okay, so very specifically, we have gone through the part with respect to quadrant. Okay, so what are the things in quadrant that we have discussed?
PAUL: the different types of memory, okay, like in-memory, persistent memory, okay, and directly the langchain wrapper, which was available from the documents, that particular function, okay. And then we looked into metadata filtering, okay, so where we looked into multiple types of filter, which are available in Quadrant.
PAUL: A very similar strategy that we have done with respect to Viviate also. Okay, but in Viviate, what was the difference? Can anybody tell me in quadrant and Viviate?
PAUL: It's about the execution.
PAUL: Or basically getting connected.
PAUL: from…
PAUL: Okay, so basically, in Vviate, we have taken a Docker instance, rather than in Quadrant directly, it was a local cluster.
PAUL: Okay, then we discussed about faithfulness, answer, relevancy, these two things again today. Okay, so when I start with the next part, the context precision recall, okay, we will go through. Because as yesterday, few people requested, okay,
PAUL: Like, very specifically, I remember Boomiga was requesting to do a mimic
PAUL: of Ragas, okay, so, like, I have created a very new notebook regarding that, where the idea is that I have kept few mimics, the idea is that exactly I won't be mimicking, the ideas that I have tried to mimic, okay, the same thing.
PAUL: Because, for example, in answer relevancy, there was a thing that we have discussed, okay, it generates questions. So, the idea is how the questions are generated. So, those examples I have taken into account.
PAUL: Okay, so a little bit with respect to the practical execution of faithfulness and answer relevancy, because in Ragas, it's pretty much direct, okay? So we will try to break that down, and we will try to understand each step.
PAUL: Okay, so with respect, because yesterday it was about the theory. Today, again, the notebook I have created.
PAUL: It took me a lot of time, so I slept less.
PAUL: But, if you check your GitHub, please open your GitHub, everyone.
PAUL: I think your GitHub… okay, so here…
PAUL: Okay, I have added one more notebook, the Ragas Metrics Deep Dive. So, first we'll be talking about this notebook, okay, then probably we will go to 10. Because in 10, it's rather than direct function calling of, RAGAS. Okay, but, the idea here in the 12th notebook, I have tried to mimic
PAUL: very close to Raga's, but again, it won't be exactly Raga's, so that you understand the practical execution of each of the metrics.
PAUL: Okay, so now, with respect to today's agenda, so very specifically, the other metrics of RAG that we'll be discussing, and finally, LLM as a judge. Okay? And next week, we'll be starting with respect to the data parsers, the different frameworks that we have.
PAUL: Okay, so docking is a non-structured that I have kept it, okay, which is basically…
PAUL: the open source ones, okay? And then, very specifically, LlamaPass and Vectorize, okay? So these are completely, like, paid solutions. Even Unstructured has a enterprise version and Vectorize also. So, these below 3 are pretty much enterprise versions.
PAUL: But at least we'll be going through that, so that you understand what is the difference, when to use, okay, how to work with multimodal documents, so those type of things we'll be, exploring.
PAUL: Okay, so I think for everybody, this part is clear, please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, so the things that we have done, today's agenda, okay, and what will be the next week's agenda?
PAUL: Okay, now let's see, that because LLM as a judge, because this is an extra topic, okay, though it was not mentioned, but I thought about covering this. Okay, let's see today if we can cover this or not.
PAUL: Amit's saying, I thought unstructured was a framework. Yes, it is actually an entire framework, but not… you cannot replace language chain with unstructured. That's the idea.
PAUL: Okay? Unstructured, in unstructured, you can do a lot of stuff, but right now, our main focus will be data parcels. Similarly, in Llama parts, there are a lot of things others out there. Right now, the major things will be focusing on the parsing part.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start… The next, part… Okay, alright.
PAUL: So, first of all, I will jump back into our notes, okay, and then we will start a little bit with the practicals, once we
PAUL: I've gone through the overview of the metrics.
PAUL: Okay, I think everybody can see my iPad, please let me know.
PAUL: Yes, Langchain is good for production, everybody is using.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, the things that we have discussed yesterday, okay, so very specifically.
PAUL: I will start with the metrics part.
PAUL: Okay, so if you remember, I told you a very, specific, this particular visual model. The same thing, I have, again, replicated everything in a notebook also. Okay, the new notebook of Deep Dive, where it will become easier for you to understand, okay, and remember going forward, rather than looking into the notes.
PAUL: Okay, so in the retriever label, we have three metrics, the context precision, the context recall, and the context entity, because these three things that we'll be discussing today.
PAUL: Yesterday, with respect to the generation, okay, so again, 3 metrics that we have. So, the faithfulness that we have discussed, answer relevancy that we have discussed. Noise sensitivity will be the last one today that we'll be discussing.
PAUL: Okay, so now let's try to do a quick recap of answer relevancy. So, if you, okay, not answer relevancy, I think faithfulness was the first one.
PAUL: Okay? Alright. So, the idea with respect to faithfulness.
PAUL: Okay? The other name of faithfulness, anybody remembers? Yesterday, we talked about that. Yes, what was the other name?
PAUL: groundness, okay? Always remember that, the other alternative name that you do have. Okay, so the idea is basically to look into
PAUL: the response from the LLM, or basically the generated answer, whether it's sticking to the facts.
PAUL: From the retrieved context. Okay, so the generated contents, should stick to the retrieve facts or the retrieved content, okay, from the vector database. That is a simple idea. If it is not
PAUL: sticking to that particular context, okay, and it is throwing some other information. We can see that there is a hallucination problem. It means that LLM is making things up.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is staying faithful to the retrieve context, always.
PAUL: Now, based on that, okay, so I've taken a simple example where I was looking, okay, so when was the first Super Bowl, and based on that, the idea was I was looking for an exact response. Okay, the date. Okay, but,
PAUL: If I'm talking about the response of the LLM, it can be much more detailed also. So, for example, there can be different type of entities. Okay, how many of you know about NER? Let me know, because a little bit about NER, it is important. In NLP basics, we always learn about NER, name entity recognition.
PAUL: Okay? So, there you know, person, location, numbers, okay, those things comes into the picture. So, very specifically, right now, in this particular response, the first Super Bowl hosted on January 15th in LA. Okay? So, as we…
PAUL: Look here. Okay, so just wait. Yes, in this part. So, can anybody tell me what are the entities here, in simple terms?
PAUL: Okay, so can I say that this is one entity, this is one entity, okay? Date and place right here. Okay, so similarly, because that entity will come with respect to that context entity recall part, okay? So that's why I thought about, if you are comfortable, good.
PAUL: Alright, now, with respect to the response, so, always some additional information that comes into the picture. Okay, so, exactly.
PAUL: Now, the idea is that what was there in the retrieved text? So, similarly, the… from the retrieve text, we can see that, yes, the information with respect to date, location, okay, and some other information, because AFL, NFL World Championship, that particular information came very specific from the retrieved text.
PAUL: Now, I told you, the first part is extracting all the claims from the generated answer, or basically the LLM response. So, what are the claims? Okay, so today I'll be doing that particular practical part. Check if each claim is supported by the retrieve context.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: It means that each claim, so whatever the question, okay, or basically whatever the answer which is generated in the response, so does it stick to your retrieve context or not?
PAUL: Okay, then comes, finally, your scoring mechanisms, which is basically the formula, claims supported by your retrieve context divided by the total number of claims. Okay? So, let's try to, okay, do the implementation, okay, so that it becomes easier for you to understand this part.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, with respect to claim scores, okay, so if I say that my faithfulness score is 1, I will say that it is perfect, it means that every claim is backed by context.
PAUL: Simply, if the faithfulness is zero, it means the answer is completely made up by the LLM.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: I think these are the things that we have discussed.
PAUL: Okay, alright, let's start with the practical part.
PAUL: Right now, I will just stop this notebook, okay, and let's jump into…
PAUL: the notebook, so everybody can take a Git poll.
PAUL: In the meantime, okay, so desktop 2, okay, so this is with respect to… Please check your, I will say…
PAUL: Okay, so here, the GitHub link is always there. Anybody who is asking in the chat, please look into that. Okay, based, directly go into the dates. Okay, so, like, 29th November. Okay, again, I think it will be 30th November.
PAUL: Okay, so yes.
PAUL: So, just click on Exploring Langchain.
PAUL: Okay, if you don't know how to use GitHub.
PAUL: then directly take a download of that. I think it will be better.
PAUL: Okay, please take a direct download of the ZIF file. So, for example, okay, so…
PAUL: Because maintaining multiple zips becomes much harder. You can download the ZIP file, otherwise the idea is always try to do a GET pool. Okay.
PAUL: Because this is the notebook that we'll be talking about, 12 Pragas Metrics, deep dive. Okay, so guys, please let me know once…
PAUL: You are ready with the notebook.
PAUL: Mmm, yes, 10, 11, 12, correct, are you?
PAUL: Actually, in 10, it's only 50% of the notebook. Okay, REST, 50%. It's pretty much advanced implementation, so that we won't be talking about.
PAUL: But if anybody is interested, later on, in future classes, we'll be talking about that. Please take a clone.
PAUL: And then let me know that in the chat, yes, you guys are ready, so that I can start the discussion.
PAUL: I think it should take maximum 1 minute, not more than that.
PAUL: Yes, please let me know in the chat with the confirmation.
PAUL: Okay, ready? Alright, fine. So, let's start the part.
PAUL: It's so…
PAUL: Thanks. Okay, alright.
PAUL: Oof, right here, so… this is the notebook, okay.
PAUL: Actually, mimicking Raga's was actually good.
PAUL: Took some time for me also to create this one.
PAUL: Alright, so right here, the things that we have discussed, okay, and now a few things that I've kept, how that other notebook is different from here, because in this notebook, it's much more about practical implementation, okay?
PAUL: So the first thing is, okay, now I'll be using OpenAI very specifically, you can use Gemini or whatever the other LLMs, it's totally up to you. Okay, so based on that, you know that you have to always change, very specifically, one or two lines of imports.
PAUL: So right here, so let's start with the first part. Okay, so right here, I'm just doing a check with respect to my OpenAI key is available or not. Similarly, if you are working with Gemini, please do have a check on Gemini part. If you are working with Ollama embeddings, then you don't need this part.
PAUL: Okay, so I think everybody is comfortable working with their own LLMs and with their own embeddings.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: By this time in this course, I think everybody should be comfortable working with their own embedding models and LLMs.
PAUL: Yes, everyone? Alright, fine.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, majorly, I have worked with Langchain, because you guys are comfortable with Langchen much more, so I've taken the main implementation with LangChain, okay? But the idea is to compare RAGAS parallel, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so the first part, here, if you look into what are the new things that I have added here, okay? So, this entire thing previously we have discussed in our previous classes. Let me know if any import, if you feel that you don't know.
PAUL: please read line by line. Okay, I feel that most of the people don't read it.
PAUL: Please go through, and let me know that, if anything, that is me.
PAUL: Asynchu is for asynchronous, implementation. Asynchu is a package, it comes.
PAUL: These are Python things, Sahil.
PAUL: For async implementation directly, we can use it.
PAUL: This is pure Python concept.
PAUL: Whoever is asking, Sahil Kiran.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, I know that, so these are the packages that I have very specifically, like, I will be working with, okay? Can you use latest pandas? Can you use latest pandas? I don't think…
PAUL: Right now, working with Pandas, really, like, whoever is telling this question, do you think that pandas is a priority? I can work with Polars, I can work with fire dust. So, really, the idea is to just create a data frame to show you. So, like, really, Pandas is not here.
PAUL: So, now, the few new imports that you have. Okay, so let's try to look.
PAUL: So, from Raga's import, single term sample and evaluation data set. Okay, so single-term sample is basically when you are working with a sample. Okay, so for example, in deep learning or in machine learning, when you are doing a prediction on top of a sample, what happens?
PAUL: You get the result for a single sample, but if you are doing it for an entire patch.
PAUL: Okay, then we call it batch prediction. So, sample prediction and batch prediction. So, similarly in Raga, it's a singleton sample that you have. Okay, so using that, you can perform a sample prediction.
PAUL: And using the evaluation dataset, okay, so this evaluation dataset use dataset from the datasets package, which comes from Hugging Face. How many of you know that there is a dataset package?
PAUL: In Hugging Face, where you have multiple type of data sets.
PAUL: You're good.
PAUL: Alright, you guys know. Fine. So, similarly, here, like, when we'll be creating a batch of samples, or simply a batch of data at that particular point of time, we'll be working with the evaluation data sets.
PAUL: And finally, to initialize all our predictions, or basically, we have to do the evaluation, because this will actually initialize all these metrics that we have defined above. Okay?
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: So, right now, you can see somewhere that I have kept, like, faithfulness, response relevancy, context precision, context recall, context entity recall, and noise sensitivity. So, these are the metrics which are directly available from RAGA. So, I'm just importing all the metrics. So, we will start with faithfulness, which is our first one.
PAUL: Now, in the next step in RAWAS, whenever you are performing evaluation, two things that you need, the LLMs and the embeddings, okay?
PAUL: So right now, the Langchen LLM wrapper, so this will help you to do the initialization of your LLM. Similarly, the RAGAS embeddings. Okay, now, a few of these, imports have changed. Right now, I am working with RAGAS 0.3.7.
PAUL: So, very specifically, I will just write it in the requirements also. Okay, and just be sure you are also using the same version of Ragas. Please don't use a different version. If you are working with 0.3.9, you might get some errors.
PAUL: Okay, because I have tested the code with 0.3.9, okay, which was the latest one, and I was getting a few errors.
PAUL: Alright, so… Let me just show you the requirements.
PAUL: I think somewhere here, if I add ragas, okay, so here you can see, okay, so I will just make it sub.
PAUL: Yeah, so just… just be sure you are working with this particular version of Ragas. So, in the chat also.
PAUL: I will paste it, okay, so that you guys remember exactly what is the version. So, you can do an UV paper install or a paper install.
PAUL: Okay, and Ragas will be installed in your system.
PAUL: I think please do the installation, and then let me know that we can proceed ahead. Because after the installation, the idea is that all the imports should be up and working in your system.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, if I show you, PYPI of Ragas, The releases that we have.
PAUL: Okay, so if you, really look into the release history, I'm picking something around October. Okay, so I haven't tested it out with 0.3.8, but yes, using the latest version, I was getting some errors.
PAUL: Okay, and few things are, like, not compatible with Langchen, because, based on the new upgrade from Langshan 1.0, there are certain things that are not compatible, so I'm just taking a version of around 0.3.7.
PAUL: please let me know. So, once you guys have done the installation, and we are ready to start with the execution. Okay, so I will just wait one minute.
PAUL: Raga says installed, don't tell me that. Okay, after installing, check the inputs are working or not. Because at the end of the day, I have told you always you can check your imports through a Python shell in your virtual environment.
PAUL: Please do have a check on Dattos.
PAUL: How many of you are doing it? Only 5 people have told done. What about others?
PAUL: Sorry, joined the class late, nothing I can do in that case, okay? So, doing… thing, okay.
PAUL: Okay, so I'll be working with 0.3.9, so if you get any errors very specific to… sorry, I will be working with 0.3.7, okay? If you're using 0.3.9, you'll be getting errors. So, very specifically, again, I am repeating, please use 0.3.7.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, strange questions are coming in chat. Do I install on Windows? It doesn't matter in which OS, whether it's Linux, whether it's Mac, whether it's…
PAUL: Windows. You have to do the installation.
PAUL: Alright, so… the first part, okay? So, let me just try to have a check, okay, by executing the imports, to have a check that everything is working fine or not.
PAUL: Okay, yes, the imports will take time, a lot of important classes that we are calling, okay? So it took around 7 seconds.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now…
PAUL: in the next step that we have, initializing the LLM and the embedding. So, Gemini part is commented, if you want to work with Gemini, fine, you can proceed ahead. I will be working with OpenAI.
PAUL: And if you want to work with OLAMA, similarly, I think you can do the initialization with Ollama. I have no issues in that.
PAUL: Yes, so let me just do the initialization of the LLM. Okay, so right now, what I have done, these two lines should… everybody should be comfortable with. This is simple line chain implementation, where I've taken Chart OpenAI and the embedding models.
PAUL: Okay, so text embedding 3 small. Now, this initialization, okay, of LLM and embeddings, I need to pass it within RAGAS.
PAUL: So, if you remember, very specifically, we have imported the LangChain LLM wrapper. Within that, I am passing the LLM instance, okay? So, similarly, for LangChain embedding wrapper, again, the embedding instance that we have defined for OpenAI, that I am passing.
PAUL: Okay? So first, initializing it using Langchain, and directly passing those instances in RAGAS. I hope this part is clear, pretty much self-explanatory.
PAUL: Please let me know the initial two cells are working for everybody, because I think there should not be any type of problems.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, so now, see, generally what happens, so whenever with our… whenever we are working with async, okay, so it becomes a problem with respect to notebooks, okay? If you are working with scripts, there is no problem. But right now, very specifically, this is a simple Pythonic implementation, so that in Jupyter Notebook, the async exists, okay, that particular async loop. So, this is nothing related to
PAUL: like Ragas or anything, it's as simple that there is a con in the Jupyter notebook. Because of that, I am applying a specific function.
PAUL: So that we can use async in Jupyter Notebooks.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes… Rama Krishna.
PAUL: Alright, now, the core part. We will start with the discussion of faithfulness.
PAUL: Okay, so the section 2, the faithfulness Deep Dive. Okay, and these things we have already discussed. Step 1, extracting the claim from response. Step 2, verify each context, and step three, calculating the score. Please let me know.
PAUL: Till this point, can we start?
PAUL: With respect to the faithfulness.
PAUL: The same stuff that I have written in the notes, again, I have done the mimic here also. Okay, so it will become easier for you to quickly do that part.
PAUL: Okay async is part of Python. If somebody doesn't know, please go and check Python. These are Python concepts.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Alright, now coming to the next part with respect to faithfulness. If you remember, this is the formula that we have discussed. Faithfulness is equal to the number of claims supported by the context divided by the total number of claims that we got from the LLM response.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the formula, okay? Now we will start with the manual implementation.
PAUL: Okay, so let's start. Okay, now, see, the idea is very similar things that I have taken into account, okay, just like based on our last example. Okay, so here, this is a test response, okay? So, this is a test response that I have.
PAUL: Okay, and this is a test context. So, I hope everybody understands what is the response. Response means the answer which was generated by the LLM. And finally, the context is basically the retrieve context from VectorDB, which we can say as GT or ST. Okay? So, ground truth or source truth.
PAUL: Now, as you can see, so this is the actual information, okay? So, let me just print this part.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, if you actually, read it, okay, so at LA Memorial, okay, so pretty much a lot of details are there, okay, with respect to the context. So, the first part that I'll be executing… Okay, so till now, nothing I have used of Ragars. It's simple variable initialization. Okay, so pure Python.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, let's start with the manual claim extraction. Okay, so right now, the idea is to mimic RAGA, so very specifically, I've taken that using LLM, okay?
PAUL: So, here, as you can see, I'm using the chat prompt template from Langshan. Okay, and very specifically, I'm passing this. So, given the following response, extract all the factual claims as a numbered list.
PAUL: Each claim should be a single variable statement, and finally, this is the response that we have.
PAUL: Okay? So this is pretty much a prompt that we have passed it, okay? And later on, if you remember, we have already discussed LCL through LCL, I'll be passing this.
PAUL: So, I've created a simple chain, okay? Now, the claim chain, I'm passing the prompt, if you remember.
PAUL: So, right now, I'm passing the prompt, I'm passing the LLM initialization, which is basically the OpenAI model, and then finally, the output that I want, it's to be string output parser. So, based on that, this particular implementation that I have done. So, this is pure lan chain, previously the things that we have discussed. So, I think everybody should be comfortable with this particular syntax.
PAUL: Please let me know Everyone?
PAUL: comfortable, because if somebody is not comfortable, it means that you have not gone through previous classes, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so let me execute this piece of code.
PAUL: Okay, and let's look into the claims.
PAUL: God is telling, please explain da. What is the?
PAUL: Alright, it will take time, because at the end of the day, it's an LLM call, okay? So, based on that, let's look exactly…
PAUL: What are the claims that we have?
PAUL: Okay, if in your case, it is done. In my case, why it is taking so much time? Let me check…
PAUL: Yes, it is Hogwarts all only.
PAUL: Let me see, yes, it should be done in 2 seconds, I also know.
PAUL: Because previously, I've executed the code, I know that.
PAUL: Mmm… Okay, alright guys, you got the answer, just wait, okay? Let me see.
PAUL: If I don't get it, then how will I do?
PAUL: Hmm. Okay. In my case, I really, like…
PAUL: Okay? So, I don't know why it took time. So, step one, so the same things, I have right now four claims. The claims are, the first Super Bowl was hold
PAUL: held on January 15, 19th, so this is one of the claims. The first was held in LA, okay? The other claim is that it was a sunny day, okay? And there were clear skies on January 15th, 1967, based on the date that we have, okay? So these are the claims which have been extracted from the response.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, Okay, so once, we have that, okay, now let's focus
PAUL: on the verification part, because at the end of the day, we need to verify all the claims, okay? So right now, based on this, so, see, right here, a few things that I have removed, okay? There were clear skies, the core part with respect to the claims that I have, that only I have taken. Or you can take the exact content also, there is no problem with that.
PAUL: So, for our analysis, we have defined the claims explicitly, so these are the claims that are coming into the picture, okay? Now, let's look into… okay, so this is a simple enum that we have defined for the claims.
PAUL: Okay, so one by one,
PAUL: Okay, so these are the claims that we need to actually do the verification, okay? So, these are the extracted claims, and these are the claims that I need to do the verification with. Because at the end of the day, if you know that, we'll be performing a simple, division operation based on the numbers that we'll be getting.
PAUL: Now, the next step is, step 2, which is the claim verification.
PAUL: Okay? So, manual claim verification. Okay, so given the following context, claim and determine if the claim is supported by the context. So, one thing.
PAUL: the context and the claim. Okay, so two things that I'm passing, okay, to the LLM for now. The context, from where I'm getting the context.
PAUL: I think everybody remembers that this is the actual context that we have defined here.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: So, our retrieve context with the click.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, Ashmin, do it by yourself. There is no issues in that.
PAUL: Okay? Now, simply, like, right now I'm telling that, two things that I need as an output. One is supported. Okay, so if the claim can be verified from the context, because here I do have the list of claims, here I have the original context. Now, let's try to do the verification. Now, sometimes you might want to get a response with zeros and ones, that is also possible. It totally depends upon the prompt template that you want to define.
PAUL: it for yourself. Right now, I've taken supported and not supported.
PAUL: Okay? Based on claims. Otherwise, you can use 0 or 1 also. There is no problem. Okay? And also, provide a brief explanation, and finally, tell me the verdict. What will be the verdict?
PAUL: the final, like, whether the claim is supported or not. That will be the final verdict at the end of the day.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, again, a chain initialization that I have done. Okay, now, as you can see, for each claim, I need to invoke the chain, because every claim that needs to be passed, so that's why there is a for loop that we have kept it, then we are invoking the chain that we have defined here, the verification prompt with the LLM, and finally, our string output password.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And finally, like, we'll be getting the result, like, is is equal to supported in result.upper, because at the end of the day, the result that we'll be getting, it will be in the form of…
PAUL: string, okay? And right here.
PAUL: This is the verification results that we have. Okay, so this is a blank list, so once we get the information, we'll be performing an append operation, okay?
PAUL: And then finally, like, we'll be getting the results, so let me just print it out.
PAUL: Somebody is asking from where do we get that test context, usually?
PAUL: From vector database. How many of you understand? Because at the end of the day, if I'm doing a mimicking operation, okay, I need to set my own values. So that's why I've taken this. Please let me know. The test response is what?
PAUL: and response from the LLM. What is that context? The retrieve context from VectorDB.
PAUL: Is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: Alright, okay? So now, based on this.
PAUL: Okay, so let's look into the claim verification part.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes…
PAUL: few things that comes into the picture. Okay, so verifying each claim against the… against the context.
PAUL: Okay, the first, okay, so for sure, this particular game will be supported. Then comes the next one, the first Super Bowl was held in LA, okay, so again, fine, supported, okay? Then this one, it was a sunny day. Okay, now the context provides.
PAUL: Okay, so very specifically, if I'm, looking into this, the context provides information about the date and the location of the first
PAUL: Afl and NFL. Okay? So, let's look into the context.
PAUL: So, this is the context. Is there anything related to sunny… sunny stuff?
PAUL: Okay, so it's pretty much not. Okay, so directly, so based on that, it's telling it is not supported. Similarly, there were clear skies, again, this is not supported.
PAUL: Okay? It means that something out of the context that came around.
PAUL: Now, let's try to, make a simpler data frame, just to show you exactly those particular results. Okay, so these are the claims, okay, so which claims are supported, and the reason, if it is found in context and not in context, okay? A simple data frame that I have created.
PAUL: Now, in the step 3, calculating the faithfulness score. Okay, because at the end of the day, you know the supported count divided by the total number of claims that we have to do.
PAUL: So, in our claims, total number of supported claims that we have is 2, and the total number of claims are pretty much 4. Okay, so based on that, okay, so you know that the result will be close to 0.5.
PAUL: Okay, so this is finally… we are getting the score. So, let me know that till this point.
PAUL: It is clear for everyone.
PAUL: Matthews was telling, can you change the, text upon text? Yes, you can change it.
PAUL: There is no problem in changing. You can change and play with these things.
PAUL: Totally up to you. I have just given you an example.
PAUL: where… from where I got the context.
PAUL: Now, this is the context that is hard-coded. The idea is that this particular information I have retrieved from the vector DB.
PAUL: This will be your intuition, that anytime, in your case, the context will be coming from the vector DB.
PAUL: And the test responses getting… the LLM is throwing you that answer, that is the response.
PAUL: Ace Majan is telling, should we not verify the extracted claims?
PAUL: Instead of self-declared claims, who has declared it?
PAUL: The same thing, it was extracted by the LLM, the same stuff that I have taken here.
PAUL: Amas Raymar's telling, in this response, getting from a physical document right now, I'm telling you about… later on, when I'll be taking the documents, it will be in one shot. It will be very hard to understand.
PAUL: That's why I'm taking a single sentence for now, so that it becomes clear in your mind exactly what is the process.
PAUL: Now, Naga is telling why the context is saved in VectorDB.
PAUL: Really?
PAUL: Now I'm…
PAUL: so many things I have taught. Now, if somebody's asking why the context is saved in VectorDB, nothing I can do.
PAUL: Can this be used to decide which LLM is working well? Yes, you can always change the LLM, there is no restriction behind that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, MS is telling Gemini 2.5 Pro says all the claims not supported. Really, I don't…
PAUL: think. Anybody testing with Gemini? Because very specifically, I'm using OpenAI, so yes, if you change the LLM, for sure, like, there can be issues.
PAUL: Okay. It works with Gemini, Rabi Basai has confirmed. Yes, I tested with Gemini, 2 are supported and two are not. Akash has also confirmed. Thanks.
PAUL: Now, somebody's asking why you are hard-coding, to show you and to make you explain, I need to hardcode.
PAUL: If I don't need to outcome then directly, I can discuss the notebook then. There, I'll be directly taking, an input, okay, and based on that, I'll be processing that.
PAUL: It's about explaining you so that it becomes easier for you. If you have a single sentence and a single context. Directly, if I fetch a big document, do you think that you will understand it?
PAUL: If it works for one sentence, the same thing will happen, because at the end of the notebook, there will be multiple sentences also, or the batch form.
PAUL: Okay? Alright.
PAUL: No?
PAUL: right now, simply, so this is the first thing that we have done it, okay? Now, let me… because, see, this is purely manual implementation, okay? So, that I have taken into account, so that it becomes clear in your mind exactly what is the process of doing the evaluation.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, okay, so I'll be using RAGAS. The idea is to verify with the actual RAGAS metric, which we have.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, what we have, which is basically a single sentence for now. That's why I'm using a sample. This single-term sample actually helps you to pass a single sentence.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, the user input, so, like, this was the question which was asked by the user, so simply, okay. Then we have our responses and the retrieve context, test response, and text context. So, these things we have already defined in the first cell, if you remember. Okay?
PAUL: And now, directly say. Just one line, I will call it.
PAUL: Okay, just one line, and I…
PAUL: So, basically, this is the initialization through Ragas. Okay, and finally, I will run that.
PAUL: Okay, so, and based on that, so right now you can see faithfulness metric, and I have to pass that single-ton score.
PAUL: Where, right now, so this is the syntax, very specifically, which was used. So, faithfulness sample, so very specifically, this entire thing that I have defined it, which is a sample. So, the idea is to pass that to your metric.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, this is a single turn A score, so ASync score that we are getting. So, based on that, so let's look how Ragas… so Ragas will take some time to do the calculation.
PAUL: If you change the LLM, yes, there will be impact with respect to the answer.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, the result of Raga's
PAUL: So, manual calculation, we got 0.5. Raga's metric, again, we got 0.5.
PAUL: So I can say the difference is zero, because right now, I can say that, yes, this is pretty much close to Raga's implementation, but it's not necessary that for every metric we can make it so much close. There can be some differences also in other metrics.
PAUL: Okay, so we can see that directly using RAGAS also, you can do the same stuff, okay? Or, like, the manual implementation also giving me a very similar answer.
PAUL: Okay, I know Murthas are evil-cated, but really, about others, I am worried. Mantaj is asking, why do we need user input? Ragas is designed in such a way. In Ragas, whenever you are doing an evaluation, you need an input. That is the format that they have defined, nothing that I can do.
PAUL: Okay, so do you want me, guys, to repeat the same stuff?
PAUL: Just tell me, I can repeat the entire stuff once more.
PAUL: Because I know for many of you, it's clear, but really, like, the metabolism of ingesting, okay, can be slow for others.
PAUL: Alright, quickly, again.
PAUL: I will just repeat myself, okay? So, let's start.
PAUL: So, right now, I have hard-coded, so that it becomes easier for you to understand exactly what is the process of evaluation. Okay, so that's why. I will be taking a document directly, so very specifically, Notebook, then you have that. But there, you cannot really understand this entire process that I am telling you.
PAUL: There, it will be a single line call, and the evaluation will be done.
PAUL: So, the idea was to break it down as it was requested by Gumika in the last class. Okay, so the… I have broken down how to… exactly the calculation is going on. So, for that, I have taken a sample response.
PAUL: Okay, and a sample context. The idea is, when you think about a response, you should think about, it is generated by the LLM. Similarly, the context that you have, it is coming from vector TV, as simple as that.
PAUL: Okay, so two things. This is the intuition that you should have.
PAUL: So, once I have defined this, the next step is… so based on the LLM response, you need to actually, look into the claims. So, that's why the first step is basically the claim extraction from the response. Because of that, I have taken the simple chat prompt template, and based on that, I have created a lang chain.
PAUL: Chain. Okay, so if you remember, these things we have already discussed in our previous classes.
PAUL: Okay, and then I'm invoking the chain, and based on that, I'm getting that, okay, in the response, there are total 4 claims.
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: Amos Rinibas for… because there will be multiple calls in the notebook, that's why I've taken ESync.
PAUL: If you don't know about async, please go in Python and learn about that.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: In every programming language, there is an async, whether it's JavaScript, Java, everywhere. Alright. Now, the idea is that once we have the claims, the idea is to do the verification. Now, see, directly, this particular thing that I have printed, okay, the same thing, I have written it here also.
PAUL: Okay, I can take it from a variable, but for now, I am not doing such stuff. So, directly, I have written it.
PAUL: As simple as that. So, it was a sunny day, you can add this particular information.
PAUL: Okay, so then also no problem, this also. So, similarly, I have taken all the claims that came around. Okay, now these are the claims.
PAUL: Okay, that I need to do the verification at any point of time. Okay, so the next step is, okay, so these are the claims that I need to verify. So again, I need to invoke a chain through which I'll be doing the verification.
PAUL: To do the claim verification, what do I need? I need the context from VectorDB. So, right now, which is hard-coded.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, very specifically, I'm telling that, okay, if you feel that this claim is supported, answer with only two things, supported or not supported. Okay, if the claim can be verified from the context, and if the claim cannot be verified from the context.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, again, I'm invoking the chain, and based on that, I'm getting the result. So, simply, you can see here, and even an explanation that I have kept it, so that it becomes easier for you to understand.
PAUL: So, the first Super Bowl was held on January 15th. Yes, this is supported, because in the context, this particular information is available. Similarly, for the second one, where the first Super Bowl was held in LA, because the location was available in the context.
PAUL: Similarly, it was a sunny day. It was not available in the context.
PAUL: Similarly, there were clear claims. This information was also not available. So, out of total 4 claims, can I say that, okay, 2 are supported, and 2 are, not supported?
PAUL: Now, based on that, simply, like, this is a simple data frame. Okay, now the next step is calculating the faithfulness score.
PAUL: Okay, the supported claims divided by the total number of claims. So, 2 divided by 4. That's why we got 0.5.
PAUL: Please let me know. Now, do you have problem?
PAUL: How many of you still didn't get it?
PAUL: Exactly what we are doing.
PAUL: Is that anyone?
PAUL: please let me know, because I know
PAUL: metabolism rate for every student is different. That's why.
PAUL: Now, somebody is asking, what is the difference between an AI response and a claim?
PAUL: EI response is actually the one which is coming from LLM. LLM is generating the output. Okay, now in that output, there will be multiple claims.
PAUL: Okay, that the LLM is claiming that? Okay, now this is the information. Now, that information is referred to as claim.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Alright, I understood, but why did all the claims got not supported? I only changed 1980. If you change the date, then also there will be an impact.
PAUL: Yesterday's theory was top. I could not get it, Sankumar.
PAUL: Context will come from VectorDB, right? Yes, when you will be actually working with RAT, it will come from VectorDB, but right now, we have taken an intuition through a hard code.
PAUL: Put a diagram, simple, all. Diagram, already done it.
PAUL: This is the diagram.
PAUL: Step 1.
PAUL: Extract the claim from the response. Step 2, verify, again, each context, finally calculate the score. Three steps are there.
PAUL: Really, like, this part, we haven't done it even in Udemy courses till now.
PAUL: Because this was a specific request, that's why I told it, because really, when you will be working with Ragas, it will be only a single line. Because in Ragas, when you'll be working with… okay, so directly, it will be in one shot.
PAUL: Really? Okay, so, for example, the Raga's calculation, where is the Raga's calculation?
PAUL: 0.5, verify with the actual RAGAS metric, yes. So, this is the part. You can see very less amount of code that you really have.
PAUL: Okay, so in Ragas, the format is, you need a user input or a query. This is how Ragas work.
PAUL: And we are passing our test response and our test contact.
PAUL: Okay? So, test context and the response, both the things that we are passing. Then, we are initializing our faithfulness with the LLM. Okay? And then we are executing that, okay, through this single return Ace code, because right now, I have a single sample. So, whenever you are having a single sample, we use this part.
PAUL: And then finally, based on that, we are getting the result. So in manual calculation, 0.5, again, in Raga's metric calculation, the same result we are getting. So I can say that, yes, the mimicking we have tried to done, it's pretty close. But in some other cases, it can be… there can be a difference. So that's why I've taken that difference calculation also.
PAUL: Sahil… you can use Ragas. Ragas is widely used. If you look into the number of stars in GitHub, okay, it's quite high, so I know people are using it in production, there is no issue in that.
PAUL: Please let me know, guys, we have other things also to discuss. Can we proceed ahead?
PAUL: Naga is telling no.
PAUL: Now, somebody is asking how the calculation came.
PAUL: Which calculation, Amar Srinivas? Please let me know exactly. The calculation is pretty much simple. 2 divided by 4, 2 were supported, and the total number of claims was 4. Directly, I divide 2 divided by 4, you were getting 0.5.
PAUL: Any alternative of Ragas? Yes, there are a lot of alternatives.
PAUL: We can use Deep Eval.
PAUL: Okay, even, RIGIL there.
PAUL: Armani Vagwandas, I could not get your question, please copy-paste once more.
PAUL: Kiran is telling display verification results as a table-facing issue in this… really, like,
PAUL: I'm not sure, I need to look into that.
PAUL: Yes, Ragat is widely used in production.
PAUL: Arman is asking which VectorDB we are using here. I have told you to take the attribution that the context is coming from VectorDB.
PAUL: Because when I'll be showing you… so, right now, even in the other example also, because if I start working with PDF, really, you won't understand. It will be directly in one shot everything that I am doing.
PAUL: Yes, the idea is, Jagapati, it should be close, because I am doing a mimic implementation, not exactly Raga's. In this particular faithfulness, it worked. Probably in other methods, it won't work.
PAUL: Okay? So the idea is that it should be close.
PAUL: Mayor, yes, it can change the impact, for sure.
PAUL: If you change the k parameter, the top K chunks, okay, so based on that, yes, it means that the retrip context is there, so it can change.
PAUL: Can we make the claim dynamic, sir? Please tell me if I don't know how to hardcode. Directly pass the variable, you can always pass your placeholders within a prompt, so there should not be any issue.
PAUL: Right now, here, if you look into… so here, if you look into the context and the claim, and later on, I am invoking the chain. So you can have multiple variables, there is no issue. You can use a for loop to do that.
PAUL: If the score is low, what will be the next possible steps?
PAUL: It means that you need to work much more toward the… for getting better response, or creating better context, as simple as that.
PAUL: Faithfulness, correctness, there is… I think I have not discussed anything related to correctness, bar and near, so don't bring something out of the context.
PAUL: Now, Naga is telling claim is coming from where LLM responds.
PAUL: SK is telling, for our benefit, SK, please let me know. Like, for our benefit only, I can see.
PAUL: Because really, guys, that's why looking into a deep dive implementation of a certain framework, it becomes very hard. For student benefit, again, I got it.
PAUL: Okay, because when I actually break down stuff with manual implementation, really, nobody teaches this.
PAUL: It was a specific request, that's why I tried to break it down, just to show you.
PAUL: I know, like, many people can digest, and many people cannot digest.
PAUL: Armani is asking, can you give me a practical use case where to use faithfulness? Faithfulness is a mandatory metric. In the last class, I told you 3 metrics are very, very important.
PAUL: Actually, four metrics that I feel, okay? One is faithfulness, every time you have to use answer relevancy, every time you have to use context recession, every time you have to use, and context recall every time. The other two, noise sensitivity, not a compulsory, and context identity recall, again, not a compulsory one.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Okay, alright, fine.
PAUL: Now, see, I will start with the next part, with respect to answer relevancy.
PAUL: Okay, because I've given it enough time, 1 hour.
PAUL: Okay, to discuss just this part.
PAUL: Really, because then I have to take an extra class to complete today's content.
PAUL: So, the idea is that, yes, you need to catch up, because the things that I have discussed, I know this is the bare minimum. It means that
PAUL: Later on.
PAUL: the complexity and the advanced level will be much higher. This is simple line chain implementation that I have done.
PAUL: And the idea was to compare Ragas with that, so that you get an idea exactly what is going on.
PAUL: Because in Pragas, it will be direct calls. So really, you won't understand the process. The idea was to break down the process so that it becomes easier for you.
PAUL: Yes, Hari Kumar. That is the idea. We are mimicking Raga's calculation. Okay, so it won't be exactly the same, but I will try to make it as close as possible.
PAUL: Alright, now,
PAUL: A few other things that I've taken into account. Okay, now, faithfulness examples with good and bad. Okay, so you know that, in this particular example, I have taken perfect faithfulness, it means that no hallucinations.
PAUL: Partial faithfulness means that, okay, some amount of hallucination that has been brought, okay? And finally, the zeroth faithfulness, okay? So now, based on this, so right now you can see a set of things that I am passing.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, if you actually look, okay, so we have 3 different contexts and 3 different responses.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: as simple, I can say, within a list, I do have a dictionary, okay, key-value Ks. So right now, these are a few of the examples that I can directly pass. Okay, and let's try to, look into the scenarios.
PAUL: So, if you look here, perfect faithfulness means that exactly from the context that we are looking for, we got the answer. Okay, so the first Super Bowl, okay, and here also, the same information that has been kept. So, pretty much, it's exactly the same, no additional information, but I can say that he has zero hallucinations.
PAUL: Now, partial, I can say, hallucinations or partial faithfulness.
PAUL: The Super Bowl, was on January 15th. The Green Bay Packers, oh, now, see, this particular information is in the response.
PAUL: But it is not there in the context, so I can say that, yes, 50% information is correct and 50% information, some hallucination that went on.
PAUL: Okay? And similarly, complete hallucination. The first Super Bowl was held in Miami in 1970 and attracted over 1 lakh spectators. But really, if you look into the context, do you think that… do you have anything related to that? So, I can say that complete hallucination in this case, okay? So, now let's try to simply
PAUL: Okay. Try to execute this.
PAUL: Now, multiple examples, so it will take some time to do this particular execution.
PAUL: Naga is asking if response and claim seem no? In your response, there are claims. Inside a claim, there cannot be a response.
PAUL: If faithfulness is low, the problem is the LLM, or the base chunks.
PAUL: It will be the LLM.
PAUL: Hallucination.
PAUL: How many of you think retrip context can hallucinate? Please let me know.
PAUL: Anybody else there in the class who thinks that red trip context can hallucinate?
PAUL: Okay? It is always the LLM.
PAUL: Don't get confused.
PAUL: Alright, now, based on this particular answer, okay, so simply, okay, so right now, the score that I've given, so here, a simple, example. So right now, for perfect faithfulness, no hallucination.
PAUL: So, a score of 1 that we have given, so here, based on that, a score of 0.33, and it's completely hallucinational, so based on that, we have given a score of 0.00. So, scoring mechanism can always be defined by yourself. Okay, so here, it's directly how Dragas is making it calculated.
PAUL: Okay, but in your case, you have to really understand, okay? That, yes, like, when I'll be talking about LLM as a church, then I'll be telling you. Okay, and even with respect to our previous implementation, at any point of time, you can change the prompt, and you can change
PAUL: basically this one, like, supported, not supported. You can make it 0 if the claim is, verified, and 1 if the claim cannot be verified. Those type of prompt-level changes, you can easily do it.
PAUL: Alright, so this part we have executed, okay, and this is a simple score interpretation guide that I have kept it. So, 0.9 till 10. I will say the interpretation is good, good to go with.
PAUL: So, 0.7 to 0.9, some are around good, and 0.5 to 0.7. Concerning, okay, so significant hallucination, so more than 30% at least, that I can say here. Okay, now, here, what are the things that you can do? Improve, the prompt, or you can play out with the temperature.
PAUL: If it is less than 0.5, it means that it's very, very poor. Okay, so, like, most of the claims are hallucinated, and major fixes that need to be done, probably with respect to your ground truth, okay, probably with respect to your prompt, everything that you need to work on.
PAUL: Yes, Matthews, we have already done it. Can we say an LLM? I don't have the information, yes, you can always do that.
PAUL: Yes, you can, run this, on an ongoing monitoring, or during the CS, you can do it.
PAUL: Based on that, you have to select an observability tool, okay? And based on that, you can always do that. There is no problem with that.
PAUL: It's just like machine learning at the end of the day.
PAUL: Okay, please let me know everybody is comfortable with faithfulness, then I will deep dive into the next part.
PAUL: So, that's the main thing. In these type of cases, try to use a good LLM rather than Okay.
PAUL: And Gemma is pretty much lightweight ones.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Now, the next one, answer relevancy, the same thing that we have discussed yesterday. So, first of all, okay, so the idea is to generate the questions. So, for example, if you remember, okay, so let's get back to our notes.
PAUL: And then, quickly, we will come back to the implementation.
PAUL: So, in our notes…
PAUL: Please let me know, can you see the iPad?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay? So, remember, so this, thing that we discussed with respect to answer relevancy or response relevancy. So, very specifically here, whether, it addresses whether the answer actually, okay, is answering the question. It means the question is getting addressed
PAUL: correctly or not. It means that exactly the information that you are looking for, whether it's available or not. Okay?
PAUL: So, for example, here we took an example, what is the capital of France, okay, and based on that, if I'm getting the response, I feel dark is beautiful. So, really, like, this is, I will say that.
PAUL: Pretty much irrelevant for now. Okay, but if you really think about Eiffel Tower as in Paris, but that particular information with respect to Paris is totally missing.
PAUL: Similarly, if you look into the other response, Paris is a beautiful city. Okay, now again, this particular Paris is coming. Again, I can say that, okay, partially, this is relevant. Okay, so, but again, that 50%, it means that how relevant is your answer with respect to the question?
PAUL: Now, the working was generate hypothetical answers, okay, that the,
PAUL: generate hypothetical, not answers, it will be question. Okay, so… this part, I have written it wrong yesterday. Okay, so just wait.
PAUL: It will be with respect to questions.
PAUL: Okay, yes, okay, that the answer would be suitable. Capture the generated questions with the original questions, and then finally try to look for the similarity. So, higher similarity is equal to more relevant answer, and lower similarity.
PAUL: Similarity is equal to less relevant answer, okay? And this is a simple score interpretation that we have discussed yesterday.
PAUL: Now, the next thing… okay, so let's try to do the, practical implementation. Okay, because here we need to calculate the similarity score. It means that cosine similarity will come into the picture. Okay.
PAUL: So, let's try to calculate the cosine similarity also.
PAUL: Okay, so this part yesterday we have discussed. Today, again, only the practical part that we'll be focusing on.
PAUL: Okay? Alright. So, the answer relevancy… okay, so answer relevancy checks if the answer actually answers the question asked. If it doesn't care if the answer is factually correct.
PAUL: Or, just whether it's relevant to the question.
PAUL: So, this is a simple analog, even in the last class that we have taken, like, it can be partially correct and partially irrelevant, okay?
PAUL: Now, this is the steps. The first is basically to generate hypothetical questions. Okay, now you know that. We'll be using a very similar prompt for this. Then, once we have the question, we will try to compare it with the original quotient, so there it comes about comparing the embeddings, and finally, we will calculate the similarity.
PAUL: Okay? So the similarity will be higher or lower, so based on that, we can take a decision.
PAUL: So, generate questions, embed all the questions, calculate the similarity. Okay, and this is a simple formula if I'm talking about, okay? So, the idea is, here you are actually calculating the distance between E generated, E generated refers to the hypothetical questions, and E original, which is basically your actual question.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Yesterday, we have discussed this. Is this part clear? Can we proceed ahead with our implementation?
PAUL: Akash Naik is asking how to query, let's say the claim is coming from the… claim cannot come from the barometric memory.
PAUL: If something is coming from the parametric memory, then probably there will be a more case of hallucinations. The idea is, right now, you should always stick to your own external data source or the parametric. I'm not, focusing on that LLM memory.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: The idea is to test the cushions and calculate the distance. Okay.
PAUL: Alright. N numbers… n is equal to the number of questions generated? Yes, from i to n, that is the number.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with this, generation phase. So again, I need to hardcode something. Okay, so that's why.
PAUL: So, based on this, so the first thing that I have hard-coded is basically the original question, okay? So, when was the first Super Bowl? Okay, and this is a test answer that we have. So, test answer… so, what is test answer?
PAUL: Please let me know what is Test Answer, guys.
PAUL: LLM response, correct. Okay? The correct intuition.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start. So, the question, these things, okay.
PAUL: Now, the idea is to generate hypothetical questions based on the response that we have.
PAUL: So, given the following answer, okay, generate exactly 3 different set of questions. Okay, that this answer would be a good response to. The question should be valid, but all answerable by this response.
PAUL: So, very similarly, I've given a prompt, and based on this structure, I'll be getting an output, okay? Now, this is the prompt structure very specifically for the quotient generation, or hypothetical quotient generation.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, I'm passing that to a chain, I'm calling the LLM, and finally calling our string output parser, okay? Now, once the chain initialization is done, I'm invoking the chain, okay? And based on that, let's see what are the questions.
PAUL: That is the algorithm. Pooh vendoram. Why we are going for hypothetical questions.
PAUL: That's how the metric has been defined.
PAUL: Alright, so right now, if you look into the generated hypothetical questions, when was the inaugural for Super Bowl played? Okay, so now, if you actually look into… okay, so yes…
PAUL: the first Super Bowl was held on. So, really, I can say that, okay, the first inaugural of Super Bowl, okay, okay, this part, the question that I feel, yes, it gives you the answer.
PAUL: Then, what date marks the beginning of Super Bowl history? Alright.
PAUL: And can you tell me the first Super Bowl took place? So, can you see that?
PAUL: Pretty much, like, 3 questions which have been generated.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, see, these questions can change, depends upon totally on the LLM. But right now, if you look into, these questions are really giving you that answer.
PAUL: what is there in the LLM response? Please have a check. All the questions looks good, I feel, because at the end of the day, I'm getting pretty much the correct date in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, and probably there is nothing, with respect to the location. You can test it out even with the location. Probably in Los Angeles that you can add it. Okay, probably, like, you can add more questions, like, 4 or 5 in that way.
PAUL: Okay, because right now, very specifically, I'm generating only 3. I prefer to take odd numbers much more. You can test it with, like, 5, 7, something like that.
PAUL: Alright, so now these are the questions that are generated. Now, what was my original question? Everybody remembers? Okay, so this was my original question. Now, can I state it? I can do a comparison between the embedding of this original question and the embedding of the generated hypothetical question.
PAUL: Because that's how we'll be calculating the similarity.
PAUL: At the end of the day, we are calculating the cosine similarity between two vectors, so I can say, yes, this is our main vector, the original one, and these are the hypothetical ones.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, based on the generated quotient, okay, now you can see the quotient, so can you tell the date or on what day? It's pretty much the context is same right now. Okay, the context is not getting changed, because this part I have hard-coded. Really, if I change the LLM, this part can change.
PAUL: Alright, so let me just print out all the questions. So, your original question with the generated question.
PAUL: Now, which step 2 is basically embedding, or the similarity calculation, where a simple cosine similarity function that I've defined it. It's not necessary to define directly, you can call it from PyTorch also, but I thought about who will install PyTorch. Again, a bigger package. Okay, and based on that.
PAUL: I'm simply getting the scores. Okay, so right now, I've just defined the function. Later on, directly, I'll be calling the function on top of our, questions.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, if you, look here, so calculate the embeddings and the similarities. So right now, for embeddings, which embedding model I am using.
PAUL: Yes, guys? Which embedding model I'm using? I'm using the OpenAI embedding model. Similarly, you might be working with Gemini embedding model. Somebody might be working with OLAMA embedding model.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is now calculate the embeddings, and based on that, we can calculate the similarity, okay?
PAUL: Very specifically, that's why a for loop that we have kept it. Okay, and enum with respect to the generated questions. The idea is to loop over that, so very specifically, one by one question will come for each of them. Embeddings will be generated. Okay, and now we already have the original embedding, which is fixed, so I'll be updating this gen embedding.
PAUL: for each question that will be coming, okay? And based on that, I have taken a blank list where I'll be appending that particular information.
PAUL: Okay? With, respect to the, cosine similarity.
PAUL: Okay, so right here…
PAUL: The dimension that I have is pretty much 1536 for our model. Now, your model might have a different dimension, but there is no issue with that. Now, if you really look into the similarities, so when was the first Super Bowl held? So.
PAUL: Question 1. Now, this one, really, that I feel that, okay, now, these question 1, question 2, question 3, all are generated hypothetical questions. Okay, the idea is to compare them with our original. So, this is the original embedding. And really, we are getting high scores right now. The similarity is high.
PAUL: Okay, so 0.93, I will say this is good, 0.8, and 0.9. Okay, so really, like, I feel that the results are good, because I am getting pretty much high similarities.
PAUL: Alright. San is asking how a developer know what questions will be generated? Alright.
PAUL: So, guys, tell me, like, if these questions are getting generated.
PAUL: Okay, so very specifically. Okay, now from here, can you extract specific quotient, and can you save it inside a variable? Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Even, I'm just telling you, let's make it much more simpler, okay? Can I say that, this particular response format can be changed to JSON?
PAUL: And where I can keep a…
PAUL: There are multiple ways, okay? So, I'm just telling you, Sam, Sam Kumara, this question, okay? So, simply, you can manipulate that.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: So, the first part, cosine, and based on that, it's done, okay? Now, once we have the final score, the next step is calculating our final score, because we have to do it for all that, because if you remember, so very specifically, we have to do it for all the samples, one by N, okay? So…
PAUL: Because of that, I'll be taking and calculating the final score here.
PAUL: The final answer relevancy, so based on the multiple questions that got generated. So, right now you can see, simply you are adding that stuff and divide by 3, because the total number of questions that were generated were 3, based on that, I'm getting 0.88.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the manual implementation with LanChain that we have taken into account.
PAUL: Please let me know. Everybody understood this part.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Now, a few other questions are there. Now, somebody is asking you, what is evaluate?
PAUL: Okay, really, I cannot, take that. Later on, you can ask me, I can let you know.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Now, let's try to directly, take that particular sample, okay, and let me pass it to Raghaz directly.
PAUL: Okay, so really, with respect to RAGAS, okay, and let's see. Because this is a retrieved context, pretty much similar, test answer and the original question. The same thing that has been defined in the variable.
PAUL: Okay, now here you can see in the RAGAS metric, this is different. So, yes, I can say that there is a difference of pretty much like 0.88 and 0.93. So, RAGAS somehow performing towards the higher side as compared to the manual implementation that we have done. But yes, somehow close, I can say.
PAUL: Okay, because, see, I am mimicking, so it cannot be the exact Raga's calculation, okay? The idea is to mimic or to bring something closer on, so that you guys understand exactly how things are going ahead.
PAUL: Already, yes, these numbers can change, there is no restriction in that.
PAUL: Mudhasar is asking, so we mimicked Raga's aspect of creating questions that answers.
PAUL: aspect of creating questions. Yes, the idea is to explain you the algorithm. In the algorithm, I told you, will be creating the questions. So I need to explain you. In Ragas, directly won't understand, because it's a simple direct call. The idea was to explain you with LangChain, how it works.
PAUL: Alright, the metrics and the numbers can be different for everyone. The idea is, see, the concept that I have told you, the idea is to mimic it.
PAUL: So that even if you want to create your manual one, you can always do that.
PAUL: In reality, how do we set manual, metric? It totally depends upon you, like, what type of metric definition you are doing. Because, here it's a small set. Later on, I can increase the set.
PAUL: But, we won't be taking it. It's easy to understand through a sample, but if you ask me to take a batch, that will be easier for me, but harder for you to understand. In Notebook 10, there I have taken a complete, bigger document, okay? So, when we'll be talking about that, you will get an idea with respect to batch much more.
PAUL: Rishi is asking, when Ragas is used. By default, the number is always 3, Rishi, with respect to generations.
PAUL: Okay, why here the score is different?
PAUL: Karthike Bhagar is asking why the spur is different, because one framework is different, one framework is different.
PAUL: Rajat Karna is asking, Paul, if we are dealing with large documents for which we don't know the retrieve context.
PAUL: How we know the evaluation is correct?
PAUL: Rajat, you have to save the context. Whenever you are doing an evaluation, you should always have the context.
PAUL: It means that for that particular query, you will be always getting the context from VectorDB. Now, probably you can save it someplace, and then you have to do the evaluation.
PAUL: Without the context, nothing that you can do.
PAUL: Okay, and that is with respect to retrieval-level evaluations. Because right here, very specifically, if you look, with respect to answer relevancy.
PAUL: Okay, so right here, I feel that, okay, so this is much towards the generation part testing that we are doing using answer relevancy. Similarly, few metrics which are focused towards only the retrieve context from the vector DB, that we are going to discuss in the next phase.
PAUL: I missed some basics, alright? Catching up, alright? Can we have a quick break? Really, guys, I feel that today's class will be long then, because I'll be completing, otherwise I have to continue the rest of the stuff on Wednesday, through an extra class, so let me know.
PAUL: How many of you feel that the thing that I am explaining is very hard for you to understand?
PAUL: Really? Because, yes, I know, Yes, for how many of you feel that, totally, surfers, yeah, nothing?
PAUL: That's why, like, going depth into some implementation, because this implementation really took me last night 3 hours to do the complete setup for it.
PAUL: But I thought that it would be much easier, because yes, when I'm writing in the notes.
PAUL: But, like, when you try to break it down, at the end of the day, this happens behind the scenes.
PAUL: Because really, I looked into a lot of blogs, nobody explained this.
PAUL: Okay, so really it took me time. That device even slept just 3 hours. Okay.
PAUL: That's why I know for a few it might be overwhelming, but really, I don't feel that the content is hard. It's just about, okay, getting the fundamentals correct.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Do you guys want a break? I can give you a 10-minute break.
PAUL: San Kumar is telling very hard explanations.
PAUL: That's why. I know the metabolism rate, everybody, because at the end of the day, totally depends upon the foundations. If you don't have a strong foundation, it will become harder, really. It's not about that I can spoon-feed you.
PAUL: iPhone, iPad cable… Okay, so let me start a timer.
PAUL: Let me start the timer, man, where is the clock?
PAUL: Glock, block, block, I'll just quit.
PAUL: Okay, so… Kyle, just have your breakfast, whoever you want to do, then we will continue with the other metrics.
PAUL: Carrange desktop 2, okay, start the timer, yeah.
PAUL: Armani, your question was not answered. Okay, probably, see, the flow is high. I can understand.
PAUL: Okay, I agree. It totally depends upon sleep. Like, if I go slow, because I feel that…
PAUL: only 2 metrics already when I have told the theory, okay, I feel that it should be faster for me to cover, because right now, even I have 5 things that are remaining.
PAUL: So my timelines, I have to maintain. Okay, so that's why. The idea is not to skip, the idea is to cover more stuff.
PAUL: Because, like, LLM is a judge, it's an additional topic. Even today, I cannot cover it, probably through an extra class that I can do.
PAUL: Okay? Because at the end of the day, when I teach some extra stuff, you have to understand.
PAUL: Okay, if I do something more from my side, you guys can also do it more from your side.
PAUL: Alright, fine, I will cover the LLM judge on Wednesday. I know for U.S. folks, it will be late. Not a worry. Because for LLM on judge, if you understand the core fundamentals, okay, they are also LLM call. Here, also, it's LLM call, at the end of the day, in my manual implementation.
PAUL: Thank you.
PAUL: I'm not even Chain of Thoughts.
PAUL: Sankumar is asking, can you please explain why the retrieval context is the answer of the question fed to the LLM? I never told the retrieve context comes from VectorDB, and the answer which is coming back is basically the LLM response, Sankumar.
PAUL: Deepaklaw calculate the embeddings understandability, getting some errors, name error. If there is a name error, okay.
PAUL: It's a simple Python error.
PAUL: Module not found error, these type of errors, guys, please try to troubleshoot by yourself.
PAUL: Otherwise, Deepak, wait, I will let you know, okay, when I will start taking the notes, don't worry.
PAUL: Can you use evaluation scores to zero down on optimal K?
PAUL: zero down directly, I cannot say it, but I can say that, yes, if the top K changes, okay, based on that, yes, the evaluation metric value will change.
PAUL: Vargan is telling, how do I set, Gemma as an LLMU Zolama?
PAUL: Sam is asking, my understanding was to retrieve context, okay. Right now, yes, I have… rather than doing the retrieval, I have taken a hard-coded example, so that you can take the intuition that I have got it from VectorDB. That's the idea.
PAUL: After using context precision, context recall, which matters more. I feel both are important.
PAUL: The recall, I feel, always, like, even in machine learning, I feel recall is much crucial player.
PAUL: As compared to precision.
PAUL: No, Mayor. Not there.
PAUL: not with respect to talk parsing. It will be pretty much about parsing techniques, man.
PAUL: The idea is you guys have worked with land chain document looters, the idea is to explore different types.
PAUL: Because really, like, when you are working with RAD, Langgen loaders, Langshen has integrations, okay, with the things that we'll be talking about, but actually directly using the framework is much better.
PAUL: So, that's why, like, from next week, it will be about the frameworks of parsing.
PAUL: Armani, you want to talk?
PAUL: I don't want to take questions now. If something is there, just let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Okay, your question is, in our case, the use case is cleared and focused on Super Bowl. If you provide a PDF document for summarization, the system can generate output with strong relevance and faithfulness. Should we call out how we plan to handle relevance and faithfulness in that solution? That will be discussed in Notebook 10.
PAUL: The same way. They will be passing it as a batch. Right now, I was passing it as a sample. In that case, I'll be passing it as a batch. That's the only difference. Rest, everything is done. Only one line code change.
PAUL: And with respect to your data loading mechanism.
PAUL: Yes, we are taking an average, correct?
PAUL: That is how the metrics has been defined, okay?
PAUL: Only roots, one require?
PAUL: Anirud, I know that, don't worry about that, because right now, my focus is towards quality and depth. That's why I've added this notebook very specifically.
PAUL: Only one student asked about this, I think, yesterday, Bumika, so based on that only, I have added that content, so don't worry. When I feel that it's important, I will always add that.
PAUL: In production, we are creating a pipeline, yes.
PAUL: Evaluating is also an expensive task. At the end of the day, you have to use LLMs, yes.
PAUL: Okay, but so many faithful prompts may be generated, isn't it? Okay, so right now, in the manual implementation, it's about the prompt, but actually, when you'll be using RAGAS. So actually, when you scale it up, then, like, directly using LLMs is actually costlier, as compared to using RAGAS.
PAUL: Somehow, Rala says that they reduced it by 30%.
PAUL: Okay, so radar becomes cheaper if you do it in scale.
PAUL: So even though is it possible to provide the embeddings to the LLM if we use the same…
PAUL: Family model like Gemini, and providing the emitting model to the Gemini model example on the structure directly on the encoder label.
PAUL: directly, passing the embeddings, okay, because…
PAUL: directly… because at the end of the day, those are numbers. If you directly pass numbers, I won't find when it will have a meaning, or at the end of the day, context.
PAUL: Pavan justai, okay, alright, Pavan. Mails, I will look tomorrow. Anybody has dropped a mail, I have not looked, I…
PAUL: Didn't have the time to go through the meals.
PAUL: Are we creating all techniques in a single pipeline? Yes, that will be within a project. Amars Shaniwas, can you show us examples on a physical document as well? Yes.
PAUL: Physical document is clear.
PAUL: That example is already there.
PAUL: No coupon codes mentioned.
PAUL: Alright, so similarly in this case, also, I've taken a few examples with respect to good and bad examples, just like last time for faithfulness, okay? Based on that, like, I'm passing it through Ragas.
PAUL: Directly? Okay.
PAUL: And then, based on that, we are getting that which is good, which is bad.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, in this particular, one, okay, so let's try to take a few. So, this is just the name that I've given, so this is the actual question. Okay, so when was this first Super Bowl? And based on that, this was the answer. Now, yes, this is highly relevant for sure.
PAUL: partially relevant, okay. When was the first Super Bowl? And this is how the LLM is responding. The Super Bowl, this annual championship game of NFL, first held in…
PAUL: general. So, yes, I can say that. Few additional information that you were getting. The annual championship game of NFL.
PAUL: Okay, now, row, when it will be low. When was the first Super Bowl? Okay, so, yes, so right now, can you see that there are no dates only? So, yes, this is pretty much, low, I can say, but yes, there is relevancy with respect to Super Bowl.
PAUL: And completely off the topic, pizza is a popular Italian dish that's spread out. So, similarly.
PAUL: Okay, so these are the simple examples.
PAUL: Through that, at the end of the day, when you are calculating the score, you'll always look into that, okay, this is 0.93, 0.72, this is 0.67, and completely off the topic, it will be 0.16. Okay, so the similarity score is very, very high, so I can say the distance will be quite higher.
PAUL: That they are inversely proportioned.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Okay, so now, similarly, the score interpretation guide. Okay, so here also.
PAUL: The score should be towards the higher side. If it's towards the lower side, it means that's some type of problem.
PAUL: So, directly addresses the question, okay, mostly relevant with some tangents. It means that some parts are, actually, the answer, the question is addressed, and a few other information is coming. So, then finally, partially relevant, missing key aspects.
PAUL: Very specifically, like in the third example, where date was completely missing. Okay, and finally, of the topic. It means totally out of the context if something is coming into the picture, okay? So always remember, these scores should be towards the higher side.
PAUL: There is only one score which is towards the lower side, that is basically the noise sensitivity. Other than that, every score should be towards the higher side.
PAUL: Alright, so let's now jump back to our context precision.
PAUL: Okay, just wait one minute, okay, I will start sharing my iPad.
PAUL: In one minute, we will start the discussion with this.
PAUL: iPhone, iPad, Mac, cable… okay, alright here.
PAUL: Okay, so just wait in one minute, we will start that part.
PAUL: All right, guys, so let's start with the next part, which is basically the context precision. Okay, so the next metrics that we'll be taking into account…
PAUL: context precision, okay? So, the same PDF that I am using. Right now, I'm not creating the ideas to keep all the metrics within the same PDF, okay? I'll be sharing the updated PDF after the class. So, first of all, here, your contextprecision.com's
PAUL: Okay? In some frameworks, it can be only precision, so don't get confused at the end of the day. It is context precision, okay? So now, if I ask you, what is the level?
PAUL: In our, metrics mental model, so very specifically, in what level this came.
PAUL: In which level? Retriever level. Somebody is telling second level, fourth level, okay? Don't get confused, okay? So, if you remember here, I told you there are very specifically two levels, the retrieval level and the general level, okay? So, the context precision comes. It means that right now, we'll be checking that retrieval quality in simple terms, if I say…
PAUL: So, right now, so the level will be the retrieval level.
PAUL: Okay? Now, focusing on the main part. Okay, so actually what it addresses, okay, so in simple terms.
PAUL: exactly this particular metric will be measuring what, okay? So, as you know that, it's in retriever level. Now, the idea is to check, okay, are the retriever chunks are ranked properly, okay?
PAUL: Arda.
PAUL: retrieved.
PAUL: Chung's… Ranked.
PAUL: properly.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the main thing that it will be looking for. So right now, see, in our implementation, till now, we have not studied re-ranking, so don't think about re-ranking right now. Okay, but this is how the metric works. So, during our implementation of re-rankers, okay, with different re-ranking models, that is totally different, but the idea is.
PAUL: The quality of the chugs, and how they are ranked.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, in simple terms, if I say that, I can say, like, it checks the relevant pieces of chance, or basically the context that appear at the top of your readable result.
PAUL: Okay, so in simple terms, checks… the top…
PAUL: K. Okay, so for now, top K, K is the hyperparameter in simple terms, okay?
PAUL: Okay, so if I take an example, during your retrieval, so just think about somebody added in query, based on that, I got
PAUL: C1, C2, C3, and C4, 4 chunks, okay? And there was Q1, the query, okay? Now, based on that, the idea is always that your chunk 1, okay, should have more information based on the query. Is it…
PAUL: Or not.
PAUL: The idea is something like that. The first chunk should have more information, the quality of information based on the query should be higher in the first chunk. Okay, so I can say that it will have somehow higher, like, I can give higher weightage to this one. So, if I simply take
PAUL: weightage as W1. Okay, so this will be towards the higher side.
PAUL: Similarly, for your next chunk, somehow the idea is now, okay, now it can be towards the lower side.
PAUL: Okay, so I know that, yes, it will be lower as compared to C1.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So somehow, like, lower, I can say.
PAUL: Similarly, for C3 chunk, I can say that, okay, now this particular weightage of W3, that will be lower as compared to C2, okay?
PAUL: And finally, this will be, like, very, very low. Okay, the W4, which is the weight H4 for this particular chunk, it will be towards the lowers.
PAUL: Site. Okay, so right now, that's why, like, the first thing, are the chunks ranked properly? It means that simply it will check if the relevant pieces or relevant chunks of the context that appears, based on your top K results, alright?
PAUL: So, in simple terms, with respect to the analogy, in the example in the notebook, if you actually go through, simply, like, I think, the example is there with respect to a library here.
PAUL: Okay, the librarian will be giving you some books. Now, your query is, please provide me the books of Sekhaved, okay? Or probably, let's take some other, like Charles Dickens. Now, the idea is that you will be getting the books based on that particular author.
PAUL: Okay, now if somebody gives you a different author books, it means that somehow, okay, you are getting a wrong information.
PAUL: So exactly, the idea is to look for precision. It means exactly what I'm looking for. That's why the precision comes into the picture. Okay, so initially, the idea is that your initial block, the top K1,
PAUL: Okay, and the first chunk that you are getting in TopK, that should have higher precision as compared to the other chunks. It means that we are giving more weightage to our first chunk.
PAUL: So that's why, are the chunks retrieved properly? Because always your rag will be focusing much more to…
PAUL: towards the first chunk as compared to the second one. But it will always look into. But if you look from actually, with respect to priority, the idea is always that the first chunk will be the main game player.
PAUL: Okay, probably it can be a condition where the information that you are asking, partially it can be in chunk 1 and chunk 2. That can also be a case, but majorly, we want
PAUL: the information to be there very specifically, okay, in our first chunk. Then, here's some amount of lower information towards our second chunk. So, our first chunk, or basically the top K chunk, okay, so if I tell with respect to the weightage, I can say the weightage will be always towards the higher side to the top one, then lower weightage to the second one.
PAUL: And finally, like, more lower weightage towards our third one, fourth one, and sequential in that way.
PAUL: Okay, Chang-year context.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, with respect to the, working mechanism. Okay, so let's try to understand the working.
PAUL: Now, the idea is, okay, so for each retrieved chunk, okay, so because, top K, so the idea is for each, that will be,
PAUL: doing, okay? So for… Each?
PAUL: retrieved.
PAUL: Chunk?
PAUL: Okay? Now, here we will be doing some type of analysis. We have to determine, okay?
PAUL: So, here we have to determine…
PAUL: weather?
PAUL: It is, relevant, okay, whether the chunk is relevant, to the question.
PAUL: Oh, let me remove that, okay.
PAUL: Okay? The idea is… so, for each chunk, you'll be doing it, it's not only about one chunk. The idea is based on that top K, that's why I've written here, each retrib chunk. So, one by one. You'll be always looking at, is it relevant to answering the question?
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, if you think about, okay, it is not relevant to you with respect to answering the question, then what will happen?
PAUL: You will get wrong information. Can I say that?
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, once you have this particular, information, so the first step is always, like, for each retrieved chunk, okay, determine that whether it is relevant to answering the question or not. Now, once you have done that, now we will move to the second step, where we'll be calculating the precision at each position.
PAUL: Calculate the precision.
PAUL: add H.
PAUL: position.
PAUL: Now, when I'm talking about this, it means that we need to give, like, at each position, when I'm talking, position means that
PAUL: So, for example, your top K. So, the first chunk was, like, position 1. The second chunk is position 2. Similarly, like, your C1, C2, C3, that particular example. So that is basically a position, the first position, second, third, fourth, based on the K parameter that you decide, which is a hyperparameter.
PAUL: Now, the idea is you need to provide some type of weightage. Okay, so I'll be, just writing here weightage by position.
PAUL: So, in the second step, you will, provide weightage to each of the chunks which are available during the retrieval process, or basically your top K1s, okay? Now, in the step 3, what we'll be doing, the relevant chunks at the top is equal to higher score.
PAUL: Similarly, the opposite, if I say that irrelevant.
PAUL: chunks?
PAUL: At the top.
PAUL: It will be… lower score.
PAUL: Yes, the idea means that if there are irrelevant chunks in the top, that is the opposite version that I'm telling, yes, for sure the score, or basically the weightage that I'm trying to give, it will be towards the lower side, okay? So let's try to take some examples, and then let's try to decode it.
PAUL: So, for example, I think, the note… in your notebook, the example is available. The same thing with respect to, I think, where is the Eiffel Tower located? Okay, so let's pick up that.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, with respect to your input that you have.
PAUL: Where is… AT located.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the user input, and based on that, like, if I, really say, okay, so I need some type of reference context.
PAUL: Okay, so… for now, reference, don't think about context, because context will be coming from VectorTV.
PAUL: The real answer is the…
PAUL: It is in Paris.
PAUL: Okay? And now, if I'm talking about… about our setup retrieve context, okay? So, let's take…
PAUL: Okay, so a few sentences for now. The idea is that there will be multiple contests, so for now, let's take four, okay?
PAUL: the E.T.
PAUL: Is… located… In Paris.
PAUL: Okay, similarly, the other chunk that we'll be having, like, badass… is… the capital of France.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Then in the next step, the other context, okay, something, some part is relevant.
PAUL: Okay, so already written T, so I will remove tar. Okay, so ET was built in with something around?
PAUL: 1899.
PAUL: 18…
PAUL: Okay, and finally, something with respect to pizza, let's add it.
PAUL: Italy. Okay?
PAUL: Now, these are the four retrieve contexts based on the question that I've answered. Okay, because, see, this reference when I'm taking, so this is the actual, response that we are looking for. Okay, so the Eiffel Tower is located in Paris.
PAUL: But somehow, if I say that, this particular chunk that I have, somehow… okay. So, yes, this is…
PAUL: The actual correct answer, so yes, pretty much highly relevant, that I can say.
PAUL: Then, the next one, Paris is the capital of France, so really that Paris keyword. Because in our question, if we see where it is located, so the answer is Paris. Okay, so in simple terms, yes, the Paris keyword is there.
PAUL: Okay, so somehow relevant, I can say here.
PAUL: Okay? Somehow relevant.
PAUL: Now, the next question, so where is the ET? Now, the question is about ET. So, yes, I got some response with respect to ET, but actually, what was I looking for? Like, I was looking for Paris. There is no Paris keyword.
PAUL: Okay, so simply I can say that this is, right now, okay, not relevant. Okay, or, like, simply irrelevant, I can write it.
PAUL: irrelevant completely. Okay, and this is, like, out of the box, okay? Like, completely… irrelevant.
PAUL: Okay, so based on the chunks that I have taken, so really, if you think about what are the relevant chunks that we should actually take into account, so I figured, initially, these two.
PAUL: One is, like, highly relevant, this one is highly relevant one, and somehow this is relevant, because actually, within the chunk, I have that Paris keyword, and our answer is actually Paris keyword.
PAUL: Okay? It means that if you really look into the precision here, the first one is highly precise. The second one, again, partially precise. In the third one, really, we are actually losing the information that we are looking for.
PAUL: Okay? And finally, the fourth one, which is totally out of the context.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Is this part clear with respect to… because now we'll be moving ahead, because, see, I have already told you.
PAUL: the examples. Now, now the question comes, I've given you an example where it has been, the weightage has been given based on this, but there can be conditions in your use case, okay, where the chunks are not ranked properly.
PAUL: Okay, and that is an example where your metric will be silly. It means that the first chunk, just think about, if I make this chunk as number 1 chunk, this as number 2 chunk, this as number 3 chunk, and this is as number 4 chunk.
PAUL: Okay? Now, here, actually, like, your algorithm will be giving lower values. It means that the metric of context precision will have lower values. It means that the chunks are not, I can say, ranked correctly, in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, so at any point of time when you are doing this, so in this case, very specifically, I've just taken an opposite example, just to tell you. It means that your metric will highly impact it, okay? At the end of the day, if there is no proper ranking mechanism of the charts.
PAUL: Okay, I'll be showing you MS, don't worry. How do we ensure the chunks are right? So, in our practical implementation, that's the thing we'll be looking for, no? Right now, the core theoretical part that I have told you. Now, in the next part, we'll be doing the calculation.
PAUL: At the end of the day, it's always about relevance, okay? Like, how relevant, okay? And actually, the answer that you were looking for, whether it is available in the retrib context, because once the answer… there is no answer only, the exact answer that you were looking for, then the relevancy highly keeps on dropping.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with our practical implementation part.
PAUL: So I will just stop sharing this one.
PAUL: Okay, and let's start with our notebooks.
PAUL: Or should I complete all the metrics and then should do the practical implementation?
PAUL: Because I think that will be better, at least.
PAUL: Because, again, one theory, one staff, okay.
PAUL: Okay, because little bit is the theory part, let's do that, okay, because… Even I feel.
PAUL: It will take a longer time. Fine. So, let's complete at least one…
PAUL: Because this, precision and recall, this is important.
PAUL: Hardly.
PAUL: The same thing, even will be going through that, so don't worry.
PAUL: Okay, so now, a little bit about the context recall part. Okay? So, with respect to context recall.
PAUL: A very similar approach. Now, context recall happens at what level? Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, so… context… recall.
PAUL: Okay, so what is the level here?
PAUL: Everybody remembers a retrieval level.
PAUL: Okay, so now, actually… With respect to measures… okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, in the,
PAUL: It's very similar to precision, but you have to really recall what it focuses on. The same thing that happens in machine learning here also.
PAUL: Okay, now the question comes, did we retrieve all the necessary information?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: dead.
PAUL: We… A retrieve.
PAUL: all the necessary…
PAUL: information. It means that there can be more chunks. It's not necessary that you define top case equal to 1. Probably, I can say that in the other chunk, there can be some type of information. It's a common problem, so we can take higher…
PAUL: sizes in production, generally, we take 20 to 50 also. Okay, depends upon the use case, but yes, we do take those samples also. Okay, so did we retrieve all the necessary, information? Okay. Now, to address the question, or to answer the question, in simple terms.
PAUL: So this is the main measure. Okay, so for example, like,
PAUL: With respect to the example, I think of examples, okay, that we have taken into the notebook. So, for example, if you are studying for an exam, using a textbook, so, for example, physics, okay, of Class 6, the idea is that you should cover all the chapters, if any question is asked you.
PAUL: Okay, it means that, did you read all the chapters needed to answer every exam question? Okay, so really, with respect to one chapter that you can think about… Okay, so the chapters…
PAUL: of all… All book, not all chapters, I can say, here.
PAUL: Books are required, okay, to… Given…
PAUL: exam. Okay, now if you have missed something, I can say that, yes, the amount of information that you will be adding, okay, from your site, and you know how that happens.
PAUL: Because right now, the set is pretty much fetched. It means that all the information with respect to the exam is available within that single book. Rather than books, let me just write a single book here.
PAUL: Okay, so that will be always… so context recall will actually ask you, did you read all the chapters to answer that particular exam question, or all the questions of that particular, exam?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And if you skip some chapter, can I say that you cannot respond to that particular question, which is a common thing?
PAUL: Now, with respect to the working.
PAUL: So here, it's much more about the quality of the information that you are fetching.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to the… it means that to answer a question, do you have all the necessary context? So, really, it is not dependent on a single context. Okay, so generally, the idea is that the amount of context will be towards the higher side.
PAUL: Okay, because most of the times, we have seen that a single query, the response that comes into, okay? So, a single chunk, it's very hard for it to solve it. That's why the idea is that you always look for that, all the information. Is it available?
PAUL: Okay, within your chance, okay, to respond to the user query instant buildups.
PAUL: Now, with respect to the working mechanism, again, 3 simple steps are there. The first is breaking down of the reference answer, okay?
PAUL: Okay? The idea is you will be breaking down the reference answer.
PAUL: Okay, for now, the response of the LLM that you can think about…
PAUL: Into, claims for now, or into facts. I think you guys are much used into claims, but facts also, okay, and into…
PAUL: Think about individual claims, just like… Okay, a single claim.
PAUL: Now, once you have those individual claims with you, check if each claim can be attributed to the retrieved context.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: to the retrip context. It means that you are checking the G team.
PAUL: In simple terms, GTST, okay, source truth, or the ground truth, at the end of the day.
PAUL: Pop.
PAUL: Yes, Sam. Okay. Now, very similar way, just like last time, okay, so using an LLM, you can get the claims. Once you have the claims, you have to do the verification from the retrieved context, and finally, the sport that you will be calculating.
PAUL: Okay? So, a sample formula claims found in the context.
PAUL: Divided by… The total claims, in response.
PAUL: Or reference for now.
PAUL: Okay? So, pretty much a simple formula that you do have, okay?
PAUL: Now, let's take an example, and let's try to. Raja Kanopal, what about GT? If everything is hypothetical, like taking the UFO? Yes, because at the end of the day, you need to make those hypothetical questions.
PAUL: Because these things are not objective, Rajo. These things are subjective, all these metrics.
PAUL: Alright, so, the first part with respect to working.
PAUL: Okay, so let's take an example, working we have already gone through.
PAUL: Okay, the same example, okay, with respect to Eiffel Tower, okay, so let's…
PAUL: I think everybody remembers that, so many times, import… Okay.
PAUL: and RC that I have to write, okay? Input.
PAUL: So, the same question, okay? A little bit, let me…
PAUL: To make it a comprehensive question, rather than looking for the exact, tell me about… 18.
PAUL: Okay. So, I've given this.
PAUL: as the user input, or basically the query, okay, and the response from the LLM, that is the idea, so that's why we are taking it as a reference.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If is an artist… Okay.
PAUL: Now, something around the belt… In 1889.
PAUL: Alright, now with respect to your retrieve context, so this is the part where multiple chunks will come into the picture. So for now, the first chunk that we have… okay, so let's take something easier, okay?
PAUL: the ET.
PAUL: Okay, is a landmark located in Paris, France?
PAUL: Sure.
PAUL: And your second one, where the built information will be, will be there.
PAUL: Alright, so for now, let's just take two chunks, okay?
PAUL: So, very specifically, with, respect to this, okay, so right now, based on this, simply, even I can add more information, okay, but for now, I've just kept into two.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: I think, yes. Now, if you really look into the chunks, can I say that we do have all the necessary information?
PAUL: Please let me know. Because tell me about ET, so the keyword becomes ET. And right now, the ET is in Paris, okay, somewhere. The ET is a landmark, so both the context that I have said that, it's pretty much correct.
PAUL: So, right now, if you actually try to look into the claims, so tell me about ET, and based on that, there can be, right now, based on this particular trip context, okay, so two questions that is getting answered, simply. Okay, so where is ET? Okay, and when was ET completed?
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, like, if you add more reference, like, where, what is the height of the ET, in that way, you can add more context. But for now, I've just kept it simple.
PAUL: So, similarly with respect to reference claims that you have.
PAUL: Okay, based on the reference claims.
PAUL: What will be the first claim?
PAUL: The main one is the location.
PAUL: The second one was, like, built.
PAUL: Both the information is coming.
PAUL: Okay, now these two are the claims, and these two claims are actually found in our RC. Okay, because both of these two contexts are there. So, in simple terms with respect to the scoring mechanism, the same formula here, like 2 by 2 equal to 1.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, like, if some other claim was there, and it was not matching the context, so by default, this value will go towards the higher side. So, with respect to the score interpretation part.
PAUL: higher the value, better it is in simple terms, just like other metrics still now. All the metrics that we have learned, everyone should have higher value, okay? At least close towards 1, that is the idea. Okay? So one, if I'm talking about what I'll be saying, the retrieved
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: The retrieved context.
PAUL: are providing… The full answers for now.
PAUL: Okay? With all the context, and zero if I'm talking about, zero simply means the retrieved context is completely useless. Okay?
PAUL: So right now, we'll be focusing on all the chunks. In precision, it's about the weightage of the chunks. So here, we don't give weightage. The actual information that we are looking for, okay, so we give much, like, the idea is to focus on all the chunks that are coming based on the query.
PAUL: In precision, it was much more about the position.
PAUL: And here, there is nothing about the position.
PAUL: Alright, now these two things, let's dive into the practical, okay? Because entity recall is also there, okay, that we can discuss after the practical implementation of that.
PAUL: So, 2-2 will be better, at least you'll remember the theoretical part.
PAUL: Totally.
PAUL: Mmm, I think you've got desktop, too.
PAUL: Only the trip chunks? Correct, Nadish. Only the trip chunks.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, we'll start with the context precision. So, very similarly, we have discussed context precision evaluates whether the most relevant chucks are ranked at the top of your retrieval results or not. It's about the ranking quality, not just whether you have retrieved relevant information.
PAUL: Alright? Now, based on this, so this is the particular formula that we have. Okay, and right now, we will be, taking this into account.
PAUL: Okay, so claim found in the context a very similar implementation with respect to, our, I can say, now, this I'm doing K. K is equal to… what is K here?
PAUL: K, what is K?
PAUL: TopK, if you remember, guys, top K, that particular thing won't be changing here, okay?
PAUL: Now, based on this particular formula, okay, the top relevant items in the top K, so whatever that K you are, deciding in that how many items are relevant.
PAUL: Okay, so probably out of 4, it can be 2 or 3, so let's try to take a simple example and try to do the, calculation.
PAUL: So, let's… understanding the ranking impact, because as I told the Vittitch.
PAUL: is there, based on that. So, based on that, a similar, same example that I have taken into account.
PAUL: Okay, and let's try to print out.
PAUL: Okay, so this is my actual question that I am asking, this is my retrieve chunks.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, I can say that the first two are relevant, and the other two are not relevant. Okay?
PAUL: Now, manual relevance classification using LLM data entry.
PAUL: Okay, it means that, through a prompt, I am telling… okay, so, given the question and the reference answer, determine if the following context chunk is relevant.
PAUL: So, we are passing all the information to the LLM, okay? Is the chunk relevant for answering the question answer only relevant or not relevant? It means that using a for loop, I'll be passing each chunk, and then it will do the evaluation, and then tell me directly whether it's relevant or not relevant.
PAUL: So, simply, a chain has been created, and based on that, I'm, executing this.
PAUL: Okay, so let me do the execution of this one.
PAUL: Okay, so directly you can see in the manual, okay, relevance classification, directly I can say that, okay, because this is a simple classification problem, so that's why we asked the LLM to do that for us. So, pretty much two things are there. Okay, so now let's calculate the precision.
PAUL: Now, based on this relevant, relevant, not relevant, not relevant, I create a list, good ranking. Okay, based on the information that I have, so true, true, false, false.
PAUL: Okay? So, you can use some other, mechanism also, but the idea is that, okay, the first one having that true information. Okay, so if it is relevant, I can say that, yes, the ranking is towards the higher side.
PAUL: So, yes, now, let's take the relevant and the not relevant part. Okay, now we'll be calculating the precision.
PAUL: To calculate the precision, what we need?
PAUL: So, right now, if you look here. So, precision good, the idea is to append the information here, your relevant count, initially, it will be 0. Later on, you will be adding it.
PAUL: So, right now, with respect to good ranking, so this is enough that we have applied, and right now, on top of good ranking, if you're looking to good ranking, the list of items, on top of which, you will be doing an iteration.
PAUL: is underscore relevant. Okay, so it's simply, like, if it will be a true condition, then the append operation will take place. Okay, and then finally, precision at K. Okay, so here, that relevant count will come divided by the total number of k that you have.
PAUL: Okay, so finally, like, here, I have taken this contribute. The idea is that high relevant thing will contribute much more. If it is not relevant, then it won't be contributing. So, based on that, a simple if-else statement that we have taken. And finally, a print statement to put the positioning of each of the chunks in that.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, the total relevant, the sum of good ranking that we are calculating, and the final context precision. Okay, now, that's why this is somehow a mimic operation, okay, we have to understand exactly not the same one. The idea is based on the formula we have taken into account.
PAUL: Alright, now, based on this, so let's try to see exactly what are the things that we have done here.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the result that we got from manual classification, okay? Now, that manual classification information, so 4 chunks I had, the first two, they were relevant, so for sure I can say that, yes, there is some amount of contribution.
PAUL: So, yes, the precision right here, okay. Initially, with respect to 1, I can say that it's 1. Okay, now, yes, because the K value, initially, it will be 1, then it will be 2, so that's why it will keep on increasing.
PAUL: Then, in the next step, with respect to…
PAUL: See, one by one, it means that right now, a single chunk with one chunk, because you have total, one chunk only. Okay, and this is one, very specifically with respect to the relevance.
PAUL: Okay, so 1 is coming from the relevance, and 1 is basically the chunk. 2, again, you have the relevance, so 1 plus 1, it will become 2. And right now, you have 2 chunks.
PAUL: Then, in the second chunk, there is no relevance, so 2 plus 0. It will be 2, divided by… now 3 chunks come… came into the picture. Then again, 2, because the fourth chunk is also irrelevant.
PAUL: So, again, 2 plus 0, it will be 2 divided by the total number of chunks, which is 4. And finally, you are getting that particular value at every point of time.
PAUL: So, the sum of contributing precision is pretty much close to 2 right here, because the final value that you are getting the precision, that is close to 2.
PAUL: Okay, so total relevant items that we have given it as 1, inside, based on that, the context precision, I will say that good ranking. It means that the order, or the ranking order of our results are pretty much good. We don't need to do any specific other task.
PAUL: Okay. But in real-world scenarios, you will be using a re-ranking model.
PAUL: Okay, because that is the purpose of… if your precision is towards the higher side, it means that you are using a re-ranking model.
PAUL: But this is the simple way of doing the calculation. Okay, precision at the rate K, that's what. At every chunk, you'll be calculating it.
PAUL: Alright, now…
PAUL: For bat ranking, so I've taken an example with respect to bad ranking also. So, bat ranking, how it will do?
PAUL: So, let's look. Okay, so initially, my first rank, not relevant, not relevant, and finally, the last two are relevant, okay? So, initially, your precision starts with a 0, okay? So, nothing, irrelevant, 0 divided by 1.
PAUL: Pretty much 0. 0 divided by 2, again, 0, then a relevancy came. So 0 plus 1, it becomes 1, divided by, now the third document, okay, that you have. Total number 3 is there, then in the second step.
PAUL: Now, in this case, the sum of the contributing precisions is towards the lower side.
PAUL: So, simply, like, 0.83.
PAUL: So, yes, it happens, so the idea is always to get a higher value for the precisions as compared to the lower side. Right now, guys, I've not done any type of normalization operation. That you have to understand. Generally, sometimes the results are normalized also, so that's why you get a result between 0 to 1.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Sineivas, normalization, normalization, I have not done.
PAUL: I just told Nana that.
PAUL: Alright, now in the next step.
PAUL: Okay, because, based on this, okay, so we have already taken this example, and I think…
PAUL: With respect to the ranking. So, the idea is, see, if…
PAUL: The idea is that if you are not having something in the first position, okay, so simply that particular contribution that you have, it will be toward the lower side.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, it means that your first rank, if there is irrelevant document, automatically the score will be towards the lower side, as compared to if you are having much more relevant documents, it will be towards the higher side.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Now, that part, we have done it.
PAUL: Now, the next part, we'll start with the comparison, okay? And finally, let's try to take with Ragas also. This part is also important, and then go through. I will give you 2 minutes. Please go through that.
PAUL: Okay, so let's try to see here. Okay, the retrib context of pizza alright, and this one, with good and bad, both the things we will do, we are doing a verification on it.
PAUL: Let's see now how Ragas, because yes, exactly my implementation is not Raga's, the idea is that there will be some amount of difference that I feel.
PAUL: Raul is asking, how does the re-ranking process… nothing we have talked about re-ranking. So, Raul, don't ask something out of context now.
PAUL: The ranking will be coming after module 8.
PAUL: Alright, so very specifically, with respect to good ranking, it is coming close to, like, 1.0, and with respect to bad ranking, so when we are actually placing the bad documents with respect to the chunks, it's coming to 0.42. So, right now, you can look here.
PAUL: Good ranking, bad ranking. Okay, so here's the difference in sports.
PAUL: So, yes, a good ranking is towards the higher side, 2.1.0, and the bad ranking is having the lower ones.
PAUL: And this difference is between good ranking and bad ranking, just remembered that.
PAUL: Is it manually given, or LLM? LLM is generating, Karthike is asking where the reference is, all the chunks of the document.
PAUL: Where the reference is all the chunks of the document, kartike, so… Generally, it will never be all the chunk.
PAUL: It will be based on your retrievable search. Right now, we have taken the example, the search is having 4 documents.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Please take your time, 2-3 minutes, go through the code, okay? And then we can continue. Not a big deal.
PAUL: go through support, because, again, we'll start with context recall. So, just take your time, and go through time.
PAUL: No, no, no, the idea is that, if you're having higher differences, it means that low and bad debt difference has to be higher at the end of the day.
PAUL: Generally, nobody does bad ranking, I am doing it manually, just to show you.
PAUL: All of your Langchen Retrievers are designed in such a way that you'll be getting good results. Now, to making your results much more better, you can use the re-ranking, that is a other concept that we'll be discussing after Module 8.
PAUL: Bumika's asking how does, Ragas decide? Ragas doesn't decide. He will be giving that information to Raghaz Bumika.
PAUL: Muddhas, sure, but, in this case, high difference point at, Raghu's code. The answer is, the ranking will be towards the higher side.
PAUL: Okay, now this particular thing, good ranking, I'm giving it a higher value. So, higher, it is better on me.
PAUL: Bad ranking, this thing. Anybody in this world will do a bad ranking.
PAUL: Manually, I have shown you to take this example.
PAUL: Just to show you, the value will be towards the lower side.
PAUL: Even if you use a line chain retriever with a vector TV, it will perform good. Nobody does bad ranking.
PAUL: I've kept it through a manual exercise. Because of that, you are getting that value lower.
PAUL: Rishi is asking, in actual evaluation, how Ragas will get the… you have to create your evaluation set. Based on that, it will be getting, no?
PAUL: Rishi, you have to create your own evaluation set.
PAUL: Puvandiram is asking how reference has been taken in Ragas in the actual well.
PAUL: This is the reference that we have taken.
PAUL: This is the reference.
PAUL: How about in automation where you'll be getting that output from the LLM, and you'll be passing that?
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: Both cannot be one.
PAUL: It can never be won.
PAUL: Okay? Armani.
PAUL: It is not possible only as margin.
PAUL: That's the thing that you were asking.
PAUL: the LLM will impact, for sure.
PAUL: check. That is a Python-level issue round that you need to check.
PAUL: If it is happening, probably use better LLM at the end of the day that… because for these type of evaluation tasks, the idea is that you should work with good LLMs.
PAUL: Gemma 3, really, it's not so good.
PAUL: Yes, Hari, yes, in the real-world scenarios, the reference will be very, very huge. The number of claims will be a long, okay, that's why those things will be towards the longer side.
PAUL: Complete DB do one, nobody passes complete DB in one shot. Hurry.
PAUL: Aruna is asking how to check whether all the context in the vector database is retrieved.
PAUL: as contact. That's the job of the retriever.
PAUL: you can just pass the top K parameter, that hyperparameter only you can select.
PAUL: I will come to that. Let's start with samples, then move to the big things.
PAUL: Kartika.
PAUL: Because to explain a single sample only, there are so much problems for many students.
PAUL: If I pass a direct document, it will ask how everything is happening.
PAUL: I think everybody has gone through the board, can we move ahead to the next part?
PAUL: Alright, Armani, you were telling that. I tried as both good and bad, and I am getting both as one.
PAUL: Mmm, really, like, need to check.
PAUL: That part.
PAUL: directly, I cannot sleep.
PAUL: We have to check the quality in both sides, the retriever and the generator.
PAUL: Actually, this is a retriever level, okay, so yes, based on the response only, you can do that. Correct such.
PAUL: Alright, let's proceed ahead.
PAUL: Alright, the Section 5, okay, so which is a context recall right now?
PAUL: So, very specifically here… okay, so here, you know the claims will come into the picture.
PAUL: Okay, at the end of the day, so let's try to break that.
PAUL: Okay, so, right here, very specifically, okay, with respect, to context recall, I feel context recall is much more important.
PAUL: Okay, like, as compared to precision, just like in machine learning. So, this is one of the major metrics that I always prefer using in rack-based systems.
PAUL: So, it will check if your retrieve context, or basically if you have retrieved all the necessary information, or basically the chance to answer the question. Okay, it measures the retrieval completeness.
PAUL: Now, the analogy, already I have told you how it works, okay, and basically the formula reference claims found in contact divided by the total claims in the reference. What is the reference? The LLM response for now. So, we are taking it. It is not a response, so we are taking some reference.
PAUL: Okay, so based on that, we have a question, okay, and we have a reference.
PAUL: And then, this is basically the retrip context, okay? So, the question is, tell me about the Eiffel Tower, and based on that, two things are there, very specifically.
PAUL: Now, let's try to print them first of all, okay? Now, we'll move to the next part.
PAUL: So, here, one more added sentence. It is, if you look here, so, like, it is 133 meters tall, okay? So, that particular information is also coming.
PAUL: The reference answer, which is basically the ground truth.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the actual…
PAUL: right now, reference response for now. This is the question, and this is the chunk.
PAUL: Okay, so if you really look into the context, you feel that
PAUL: All the context that there are not. First stop will tell.
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: Q field, all the context is there.
PAUL: Ariane is telling yes. Ariane, how you are telling us, man?
PAUL: That 330 meters tall, where is that information in the context?
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Okay, now let's…
PAUL: correct, based on our reference claims. So, can I say that these are the reference claims that I have?
PAUL: Say it simply.
PAUL: Three sentences.
PAUL: those 3 sentences I have taken into account, okay?
PAUL: These are my reference claims, okay? Now, these reference claims, I'll be passing with the context to have a check.
PAUL: Alright, now… okay, so, based on this, can the following claim be attributed to found in the given context? So, where you were passing the context.
PAUL: and the claim. Answer is, if the claim is supported by the context, no, if it cannot be found. Then, I'm creating a chain. In the next step, I'm invoking the chain, and based on that, let me see how I'm getting my answers.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so it will take some time. The first one was found. Okay, so you can directly see that it's telling that, okay, now this is missing.
PAUL: The third claim, which was there in the reference, that particular information is missing from the context, so that's why this information was not returned. That directly, we are calling it, okay? Now, the idea is, based on that simple formula, the claims found
PAUL: Then you have your total claims, okay, and your manual record. The idea is we are doing the calculation manually, so simply that division operation. Claims found divided by the total claims.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, alright,
PAUL: Okay, no, just wait. I think I need to exclude this one. Yes. So here, I'm getting a score close to, like, 0.67. The context we call interpretation, 33% of the required info was not retrieved. In simple terms, right now, I can say that
PAUL: Okay, I can take an interpretation based on this particular value. Similarly, with respect to RALAS, okay, when I'm doing the execution, let me see.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, Ragas is also printing the same thing. So, Ragas underscore recall, okay, and based on that, 0.67. So, I can say that this time, our implementation that we have done, it's pretty much close to Raga's.
PAUL: Okay, because the values are coming very, very close.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Let me know, let me know, guys.
PAUL: Ravi is asking, should the context be recall context?
PAUL: No.
PAUL: Check this…
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, this is an easier implementation as compared to the precision part.
PAUL: So, please check what I have done.
PAUL: Saurabh is telling you using Ragas is much simpler than a manual. He has 4 should.
PAUL: Reference is the golden truth for now. Yes, you can think about Karthike.
PAUL: that we are not expecting RTK. It is, you have to think about, it is the response from the LLM. That's why we're taking it as a reference.
PAUL: All right, Amit.
PAUL: Please let me know with this particular implementation.
PAUL: Because, very similar approach, just like last time we have done, with respect to answer relevancy.
PAUL: So there, it was about generating the questions. Here, we are actually checking the claims.
PAUL: Are correct or not based on the retrieve context.
PAUL: Everybody is asking, okay, we are doing manually, there you have to create an evaluation set, and then you have to pass it.
PAUL: Ravi Basai is asking, where is the context variable coming from?
PAUL: Muntasar is asking…
PAUL: Had there been a missing point in the reference length, then I would say that the precision of the rag
PAUL: will be less. Yes, you can say that.
PAUL: So, for sure, see, precision is much more about the ranking of the charts.
PAUL: Recall is not about the ranking part.
PAUL: Okay, so don't get confused there at any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, so don't try to compare. So you can think about, yes.
PAUL: Somehow, if your recall will be towards the lower side, for sure your precision will be towards the lower side.
PAUL: But generally, with respect to context precision, there can be a case. Just think about enduring your context precision. Your top K result was good, okay? But really, only the first chunk that you had, it had the correct information, but the others didn't have.
PAUL: Okay, so that first chunk will have higher weightage. So, because of that, there will be an impact with respect to the final result that we'll be getting. So somehow, the precision will be toward the higher side, because their ranking plays a crucial role, but not here in recall.
PAUL: Ravi Wazar is telling Cell 13. What is cell 13?
PAUL: Alright, we'll have to, take it off, okay, alright, later on, we will go through.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Fine.
PAUL: Okay, because the next part will be now starting.
PAUL: Okay, Vishnu is telling, recall score… okay, what is there in the recall score? Vishnu?
PAUL: Yes, correct understanding, Akash Naik. As per my understanding, the reference is coming from the LLM response, but
PAUL: When we can see the faithfulness from the LLM is hallucinating as, okay, now…
PAUL: Alright, the context recall pop, it is like some of the claims from the reference response from the LLM is not existing in the context, so that the context recall is not good. In that way, we are thinking it is correct, but are they kind of somewhat same, but in different understanding? One.
PAUL: K…
PAUL: Your understanding is correct, Akash. Okay, but that later part, okay, are there kind of somewhat same? I cannot directly say it is same.
PAUL: Okay, there is a difference.
PAUL: Alright, fine guys, so let me know, can we proceed with our other, metrics now?
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: Vishna is studying, what if the missed claim is an LLM, hallucination?
PAUL: Okay, then it will be handled by faithfulness. Yes, it can be a scenario.
PAUL: Okay, yes, it can be a scenario, Vishnu, the thing that you were asking.
PAUL: Sanjeev Kumar is telling it's really difficult to follow as the things are hard-coded. Really, like, if the things are hard-coded, it's always easy to answer.
PAUL: Okay? Because, see, don't worry, the idea was to take you an example and show you. Later on, going forward, I will never show you these things, and directly I'll be calling Ragas, so that you guys internally understand what happens.
PAUL: Okay, it's totally, like, one choice.
PAUL: to Ada.
PAUL: Because really, it totally depends, that's why it always have a mixed scenario. Few students don't like this stuff directly, rather than calling functions. Because I know few people are smart, and they can directly look into the RAGAS implementation.
PAUL: Okay, so anybody who is a Python developer, they can do that. But others, it becomes hard.
PAUL: Should you use precision recall every time? Yes, I will say that use.
PAUL: I feel that context precision and context recall, faithfulness, okay, and answer relevancy. These four are very, very important. You can actually skip entity recall, really not so much important, or, noise, sensitivity.
PAUL: Just think about the metrics that we are defining, it is not available in every framework.
PAUL: Okay, it's very specific to this RAVAS part only. Now, based on RAVAS, we are doing that particular implementation.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Alright guys, okay, now we'll move to the next set.
PAUL: Alright, okay, so let's…
PAUL: entity recall, okay? So, a little bit about the entities, if somebody doesn't know about NER. Okay, so…
PAUL: If you don't know, please later on go and explore that. Look at name entity recognition.
PAUL: Alright, now we will start with the next part.
PAUL: Let's get back to your notes.
PAUL: Ducks.
PAUL: top, I think it will be the advanced via iPad via cable.
PAUL: Yes, Charanthija, multimodal metrics are also there.
PAUL: In Ragas, correct? Two multimodal metrics are there.
PAUL: So, iPhone or hardware cable, already.
PAUL: Yes, Prakash, for everything you need labeled data at the end of the day.
PAUL: without an evaluation set, you cannot do anything that I have told till now.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: So, let's take, the next part, okay?
PAUL: So… Okay, alright, I think, yes, it is scrolling up fine.
PAUL: Now, coming to the part with respect to, defining the
PAUL: context entity, okay? So, for the context entity, few common things, as I told initially in the start of the class, okay, like named entity recognition, simply, like, at least the basic ones, that I feel that
PAUL: You should know that within a sentence, if there is London, okay, it refers to one of the entities, and that entity is particularly a location, okay? Or it can be a person, for example, if I say that, okay, so, like, Raul is going somewhere, okay, so that Raul becomes a person.
PAUL: PB. Okay? So, similarly, based on that entity, the idea is that we will actually try to focus on the entity within a context on this. Okay, so that's why this particular, context came up, context recall.
PAUL: So, with respect to context recall…
PAUL: Okay, so the measures part.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, the working part. So, what you'll be measuring in the first step?
PAUL: Did we retrieve the… did we retrieve the context containing all the important entities? Okay? So…
PAUL: We retrieve the context.
PAUL: Containing… okay.
PAUL: all necessary entities for now that I'm defining.
PAUL: Okay, in bracket, example of the entities, if I want to provide you, like, people, places, organization, date, that you can take, okay? It can be people, place.
PAUL: Okay, organization, date, numbers, okay, so those all things that comes into the picture under entities.
PAUL: Okay, so right here, now mentioned in the reference answer. Okay, now all these things will be mentioned where?
PAUL: In the reference answer means LLM response.
PAUL: Okay, it means that, see, did we retrink the context? Okay, having all the important entities.
PAUL: Okay? Now, generally, you will ask, Paul, where will be the entities? Entities will be in your reference answer, for now.
PAUL: Okay? The idea is that, are we retrieving all the context?
PAUL: Containing all the important, entities, okay, which are mentioned in our reference answer. So, for example, if I take something like that… okay, so let's take a simple analogy for now.
PAUL: Something like, a famous person, Albert Einstein example, I've kept it in the notebook. Okay, now, alright, so let's…
PAUL: Take, first of all, the reference.
PAUL: Let's take a simple name, like…
PAUL: Okay, so right now, how many entities I have?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay? I have 3 entities.
PAUL: Okay, so… Person.
PAUL: Paul. Okay.
PAUL: Then comes… Location.
PAUL: London.
PAUL: Person, location, and finally, comes your date.
PAUL: Okay, now the idea is that, see, from the reference, I am trying to extract the named entities. Okay, now this is the part with respect to extraction, because, see, I've taken a simple sentence, really, for now.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part with respect to the extraction, the first phase that happens, okay? Extraction from where? From?
PAUL: Reference.
PAUL: Reference for now, you can think about the LLM response in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, so if I'm talking with respect to the working part, The first step is extract.
PAUL: Okay? Named entities.
PAUL: Because based on entities, you will be looking into the retrieve document, okay? Now, once you have done the extraction, extract.
PAUL: In the next step, what will you be extracting?
PAUL: Extracting the named entities.
PAUL: from RC. Retrip chunks, okay, or retrip Context. Okay, extract entity from reference. Don't get confused. Okay, so here, like, reference, this is the one.
PAUL: Two things. In both the place, it's all about the extraction. In the first case, it's about extracting the named entities from your reference answer, then in the next step, extracting entities from retrieved context. Okay? And finally, you'll be calculating the score.
PAUL: With respect to score, entities… okay, so…
PAUL: divided by… entities. Okay, now what are the entities that will come?
PAUL: Entities in reference.
PAUL: and entities in… the total entities, if I'm talking about.
PAUL: Okay, so for now, total entities, let me just write, I think that will be better.
PAUL: It only be with respect to,
PAUL: The idea is that we take both the entities from the reference answer as well as from the retrib context. Okay, so for now, let me just write, both here.
PAUL: Okay, because total entities, you can think in that way, okay?
PAUL: Abhishek is asking, what does reference mean? For the last one hour, what I was telling.
PAUL: think about it as a LLM response.
PAUL: Okay? Alright. Now, based on this, that, let's take a simple example, okay? And now, in this particular case, with respect to…
PAUL: The score interpretation, just wait, guys.
PAUL: Alright, so just wait. I will… Where is the venue?
PAUL: Yes, I will come to that, but before that, let's take an example, okay? And let's try to understand in, simple terms that what we are referring here.
PAUL: So, first of all, at any point of time within the reference, there will be entities, and majorly it happens in most of the cases. Okay, so…
PAUL: With respect to your… Rather than writing it, the sentence is always towards a bigger site.
PAUL: In the notebook, the example that you have… okay, so, like, I think…
PAUL: There, just look into the notebook, you will get it. Yeah, so, Albert Einstein.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, developed relativity at Princeton University in 1905.
PAUL: This is… A reference, okay.
PAUL: In 1905, okay? So, right now, this is R.
PAUL: REF for now, reference, that I'm talking about. Now, based on this, you have your RCs.
PAUL: the retrieve context. The first sentence can be, like, Albert Einstein was a famous physicist, or something like that.
PAUL: Yeah.
PAUL: Alright. Now, one of the entities, this is covered.
PAUL: Okay? Albert Einstein, which is a person. So right now, in this reference, what is the other entity?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: How many other entities are there?
PAUL: PU and 1905, okay, so PU, the Princeton University, okay, and then 1905. So, these two things are others. So, right now, really, if you, look here, okay, and directly if I say that, if I have only this piece of context, for now, a single context that I am taking into account.
PAUL: Okay, because entities in reference.
PAUL: It is, okay.
PAUL: ET… not Eifelta, okay, don't get confused.
PAUL: Entities in reference.
PAUL: reference, if I say.
PAUL: three entities are there, okay? So, Albert Einstein, that is one. The other one that you have is PU, okay, which is basically the location, and the other one, there is a date.
PAUL: So, 3 entities for now, in reference that I have. Now, entities in context, retrieve context.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to retrieve context, How many entities are there?
PAUL: one entity.
PAUL: And that one is B.
PAUL: Okay, so for now, just a simple one that I have taken.
PAUL: I have reference context, there is no such thing reference, it's just reference, Armani, for you, okay? RC means retrieve context.
PAUL: No. Okay.
PAUL: physicist, directly, we can say it is not a person, okay? So, directly, that's not an entity.
PAUL: Are females at the retrieve context.
PAUL: Okay, anything in confusion here, please let me know.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, with respect to…
PAUL: Your scoring part. Okay, so if I try to do a match analysis, okay, so simple. Let's try to do one match, one match, no match, no match.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, like, what will be the value with respect to the scores?
PAUL: in total.
PAUL: if I'm talking about, in total, how many, things that you have with respect to the references.
PAUL: Okay? The world looking, rather than just weight.
PAUL: Okay, so this part, if I take it as… Okay, A comma B.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, with respect to reference, it will be towards the lower side.
PAUL: And… just tweet.
PAUL: I'll be just making it towards the smaller side, okay? So, based on the formula, entities in the reference, that we have 3. And here, entities with respect, okay, because rather than re… let me just remove both from here.
PAUL: Okay, I will just keep it in RC, I feel it. It will be better to understand based on my explanation.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Matching with reference.
PAUL: Okay, so I've added matching with reference, because that match, that needs to be maintained here. So right now, if I try to, do based on this particular analysis, what will be the score?
PAUL: 1 divided by 3, because only 1 got matched. Okay, so pretty much, like, 0.33. Okay? Now, in this particular sentence, Albert Einstein was a famous physicist. Here, if I add NPU, okay? In Princeton.
PAUL: Nope.
PAUL: I can say that, okay, now this part got updated, so one more interior that came, which is the view here. Okay, now, based on this in RC, this got updated to… to…
PAUL: Okay, and now this particular value will change.
PAUL: to somewhere close to 6, 7, around. This is a rough estimation that I have taken for now, just to show you that particular calculation.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes.
PAUL: So, right now, if you think about, I can say that 60% of the entities, in simple terms, that were matching with respect to the available in the reference, as per the retribed context, or the retripped entities within their chunks.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, okay, here it's a simple matching mechanism between your
PAUL: reference entities as compared to your RC entities, or retrieve Context entities.
PAUL: Hmm, what is the best, metric found?
PAUL: There is nothing called a best metric, Sunibar.
PAUL: Okay? If somebody asks me what is the best metric, nobody can tell me.
PAUL: Okay, there is no such thing as this is the best metric.
PAUL: Alright. Now, based on this particular implementation, so let's try to look… I hope everybody got it. It's very, very simple. You just try to analyze the entities in both reference and retrie context, and based on that, a simple division that you have to do.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to the retrieved context divided by the entities of the references.
PAUL: So, based on that, so let's try to take an example.
PAUL: Yes, you can use NLTK NER, Shivandar Singh, correct.
PAUL: Okay, analytical space, anything that you guys can use. So, desktop tool…
PAUL: Alright, so the same thing that I have tried to… Okay.
PAUL: Because in this particular formula, okay, as you can see here, in this notebook, I've kept it entities in both reference and context.
PAUL: So, generally, like, when I'm actually looking into this formula, okay, now, based on the implementation, my values are coming towards the lower side, okay, because this formula was available in RAGAS.
PAUL: That's why I've kept it, like, entities in both for now, because even with respect to our main implementation, directly I'll be using the RC on top of that, okay? So let's try to do that.
PAUL: So, right now, the entity recalls setup, okay, so let's try to look into the setup, and then we will try to take the reference, and as well as the both in the implementation.
PAUL: So, entity reference. So, first of all, the same thing that I have discussed, and the same thing. Okay, so let's take some examples.
PAUL: What happened? There is a named error, LLM is not defined.
PAUL: I think LLM has been defined.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: So the first one, I have defined exactly what are the entities, like, entity reference and entity context. Okay? So, these two things very specifically that I have taken into account based on that, these are the two examples. Now, the first step is extract the entities in both the places.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, simply, entity extraction prompt. Okay, so right now, as you can see, this is an NER task that we are telling name entity recognition task that we are telling the LLM to do, extract all the named entities from the following list.
PAUL: Okay? So, right here, as you can see here, other proper nouns also that we have kept it, but not necessary every time.
PAUL: So right now, the main text, okay, so this is our main text, which is a placeholder that later on, it will be, changed.
PAUL: And then finally comes our entity chain. Okay, so this particular prompt. So this is a simple NER task. Can I say this is an NER task I am doing? On top of
PAUL: What?
PAUL: the reference.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: We are performing a simple name entity recognition task.
PAUL: On top of the reference.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, as simple, the idea is to extract the entities. Based on that, I've taken that.
PAUL: Okay, hand manual, extraction of the entity of our reference, if I look into Albert Einstein. So, this is the actual text that we have.
PAUL: Okay, so based on this, you can see the reference entities that we have, and similarly, we are invoking the chain for both the entities. Okay, so one for our reference entities, one for our context. CTX entity stands for our retrieve context.
PAUL: Okay? So, in this particular case, there, we have 3, okay? And here we have 2, okay? So, let's take that example.
PAUL: Okay, now, manual entity analysis. Okay, so define the entities. So, the reference entities… okay, manually you can do it, because right now I'm not saving it inside a variable, so manually I have hard-coded it.
PAUL: Tell what use cases we need to manually entail, what works for the reference?
PAUL: No guardigate. You don't need to create references. Then, actually, like, you will be always having the LLM response with you, okay, in real-world scenarios.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, see, well, manually, I'm creating both. So, based on this particular output, I created both, so pretty much a hard-coded operation that I have done. Then, entity, comparison. Okay, so entity and reference type found in context.
PAUL: Okay, a simple print statement that I kept, just to show you, okay? So, the found underscore count initially, a flag variable, okay, with 0. Now, for entity comma, entity type, intreference underscore entities dot items.
PAUL: Okay? So, the first one, with respect to reference entities, so, like, through items.
PAUL: We are looping over that entire dictionary, where very specifically, we have three, I can say, entities, and based on that, what is their exact entity? That also, we have mentioned here.
PAUL: Okay, so found in any, so on top of that, we are applying entity.lower in ctx.lower. So, this is a simple condition that we are fetching.
PAUL: I hope, using any, I am doing a fetch operation, that found operation.
PAUL: The idea is to perform a match, so simply I am doing that. Entity lower in ctx.lower.
PAUL: Simply ctx lower in entity.lower. In both the way, I'm looking if it exists or not.
PAUL: How many of you understand this particular Python operation?
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: If you are not comfortable, okay, you can break this statement and write it.
PAUL: Alright, now the question comes, if it will found, okay, if found is equal to true, then we will increase the found count.
PAUL: which is 0 plus 1, simply. We are increasing the counter, and status is equal to yes, if found else missing. And finally, we are printing out the entity, entity type, and the status, okay, based on that. So, let's try to look at…
PAUL: Okay, so exactly what is there? So, entity with respect to the reference. So, yes.
PAUL: Albert Einstein, these are now type person, now found in context. The first two things that we found, and finally, this was missing, which was the date one.
PAUL: Because directly I know that, yes, there is no such date only. So, yes, I know that, okay, this particular information was not available in our reference entity dictionary, so because of that, it's showing you that missing part.
PAUL: Now, with respect to the, entity recall calculation, that we have done it, okay?
PAUL: Found count, okay, so how many that we found that were actually there, okay, divided by the length of the reference entities is equal to record. Okay, so directly you can see in the implementation, if you directly think about it, about the how many entities that we found.
PAUL: So that's why this AND operation, that came. Because here, right now, you are doing a matching. So, because of that, that both part that I kept, so directly don't think that it is with respect to the retrip contest, but actually how many matched?
PAUL: Okay, so simply, like, if I change the markdown.
PAUL: Okay, so it will be easier for you to understand.
PAUL: Okay, so here, entities matched, okay? So, entities in both.
PAUL: Reference on context, let me add unmatched here.
PAUL: So that's why very specifically I kept that matching part.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, based on that matching, only 2 things that match, 2 divided by 3, so based on that, I got the answer, which is around…
PAUL: 0.67. The same thing, manually, we have done the implementation. Now, let's see how Ragas is throwing the answer.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, Raga's metric… okay, now manual estimation, you can see. Here, our implementation looks like somehow a bit different. With respect to Raga's metrics, I'm getting 0.25.
PAUL: Okay? And here, I'm getting, like, 0.67. So I can say that, yes, there is a difference that is coming with the
PAUL: Actual RAGAS as compared to our manual implementation.
PAUL: Hari Kumar, not clear which part, Hari. Karthi case, sir, but in, context recall, we need to pull through the response and the reference in Raga sent text, but here it's not required.
PAUL: It totally depends upon, like, which one that you are taking into account. Every metric has their own way of taking the input.
PAUL: the difference will be there, because I'm… the implementation is different, that's why I told you. I've tried to mimic, but every time you don't think about it, you will be getting exactly the same answer. There will be differences in other metrics also.
PAUL: Aryan is asking, can we check the entities found or not directly in Ragas? Directly not available. In Ragas, you can't do that.
PAUL: You have to actually change the source code of Ragas.
PAUL: Okay, then you can do it.
PAUL: You have to go to the actual package. Within there, you have to look for the implementation, and then, actually, you have to do a lot of changes.
PAUL: Okay, then you can do that, at any point of time.
PAUL: If you're a Python developer, you can do it. If you are not a Python developer, it will become a problem for you.
PAUL: Okay…
PAUL: Which is accurate. Now, totally see, Ragas is his own. I cannot say that this implementation or that implementation is correct.
PAUL: Because this is the core actual implementation, main on the theoretical part. So, for sure, the implementation that I have done, it's pretty much nigh.
PAUL: In Ragas, I feel that it's much more powerful, as used widely.
PAUL: The thing I'm showing you is just a normal variant version.
PAUL: Just to think that's exactly how things work around.
PAUL: Okay, so there is no such thing as about accurate. If you are going with framework, similarly with deep eval.
PAUL: Directly things will come to you. But exactly the working of every metric takes place in this way.
PAUL: Please check, guys, I feel that this implementation is much easier as compared. A simple matching operation that you are doing, and based on that, you were doing the calculation.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Apart from Ragas, is there any… there are so many frameworks, Sharant Teja.
PAUL: In your manual calculation, one entry and roughness entity is missing, that's why the scores are different. Alright, Rabbi is telling that one entity is missing.
PAUL: So, very specifically, if I look into, here, two entities that I have, it's correct. Here are also two entities.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the part with respect to context, this is fine, entity comparison. Here I am finally doing the check. Okay, now let's look into LAGAS.
PAUL: Raga's part, entity, reference, okay, alright, and the entity context. Because directly, I have passed it here.
PAUL: Because this is a direct sentence that I have taken, and the entity context, okay? Let me see once the entity context.
PAUL: Alright, this is the entity reference.
PAUL: I don't think Czech rugby.
PAUL: Okay? Relativity is not there, you were telling.
PAUL: Okay, relativity is not there. Okay, let me check, because…
PAUL: Entity reference… it's telling one word is missing. Let me see this one.
PAUL: Because this is the same entity reference and the entity context that we have passed it here. I have not overwritten the variable somewhere.
PAUL: Okay, I feel that it's correct. Ravi, later on, you can show me your implementation, okay?
PAUL: Because this is the same variable that I have done the initialization.
PAUL: At a later point in Trava. So, really, I'm not changing that part.
PAUL: Is it possible in Rava Springs that it's considered as a location? No.
PAUL: It's Princeton University.
PAUL: Okay, Karthik is asking, is it possible in Ragas? Princeton is considered as location, and Princeton University is,
PAUL: Considered as an organization. Okay, so generally, like, if it is Princeton University, then it becomes a phrase. Like, through bigrams, we can actually detect, like, it's pretty much like an organization.
PAUL: Okay, so that detection happens through classical NLP directly, like, it works.
PAUL: With respect to… Any implementation.
PAUL: Alright, so this entity recalled with the Ragas is trustable… DS?
PAUL: I can say that it is trustable. In both the cases, the implementations are correct. So, yes, the results are trustable at any point of time.
PAUL: All right. Now, we will move to the final part with respect to noise.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, I feel that this is the last one, and an easier one to implement.
PAUL: And really, like, noise sensitivity is not available in other frameworks. It's very, very, very specific to RAGAS only.
PAUL: So, let's try to complete this part, okay? So, this part, I'm not writing it in the notes, okay, because I feel that… let's quickly, because what is noise in simple terms? Please let me know.
PAUL: Guys, what is noise in the field of entire deep learning?
PAUL: Error, no. Mantage is telling error, incorrect.
PAUL: Unrelevant, yes, irrelevant, okay. Actually, the term is soil is calling unwanted information, in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Somebody's feeling bias.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: Okay? It's always the unwanted information. Okay? So simply, that is referred to as noise.
PAUL: What is the other name of noise?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: What is the other name? Outlaws? No. No. No.
PAUL: Noise is referred to as jitter.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So first of all, here, so let's start, okay, with our, simply, like, noise sensitivity, you know that it will be calculating what is the unwanted amount of information that you have, okay? So, the idea is that how much that jitteriness you got from the data.
PAUL: So, you are taking, so right now, sensitivity test, how much irrelevant information in the context causes error in the answer? It measures robustness to noise, as simple as that.
PAUL: So, how much irrelevant information that you have? Okay, or basically unwanted information, the information actually you are not looking for during retrieval, okay?
PAUL: So, now, for sure, that will cause
PAUL: Errors, okay, or basically unwanted junk, okay? Simply, in your final answer. Okay, and that's why it is widely used for measuring the robustness towards the noise, so how much it is highly tolerant.
PAUL: Now, the analog, it has been taken years, so if you're taking an open book exam, but someone makes random Wikipedia articles into your notes. So, yes, noise sensitivity measures how often these random
PAUL: articles cause you to write wrong answers. It means that some type of external induction that happened. So here, the external induction will be with respect to retrieving wrong
PAUL: context from the vector team. Okay, because of that, yes, noise can come into, I can say your final answer, or basically the LLM response.
PAUL: Now, this is the only metric till now that we have learned, okay, where the value should be zero.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is that 1 is the worst, 0 is the best. Okay, till now, this is the only metric. In other metric, the interpretations can be taken as, okay, higher is always better, but this is the only one, okay, where 0 should be there.
PAUL: Now, so first of all.
PAUL: Based on the formula that we have, okay, so the noise sensitivity, okay, so here, I think the working part is not there, okay? So, okay, let's get back to the notes, because that part is important.
PAUL: with respect to incorrect claims. So, how many of you understand that how the incorrect claims will be calculated? Please let me know.
PAUL: At the end of the day, whenever you are doing, the process is pretty much simple, just like last time, okay? So, just wait, I will start sharing the notes.
PAUL: Okay, because the working part is not written in the notebook, so desktop 2.
PAUL: ship.
PAUL: Okay, so I think, again, I have shared the same notebook only, just with advanced iPad via KPL, okay?
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, so now with respect to the final one, so let's focus on that working part.
PAUL: So, noise sensitivity.
PAUL: So, directly, I can say that this is pretty much junk.
PAUL: Okay, so generally the term noise refers to unwanted data.
PAUL: Okay, generally, with respect to graphs, we call it jitter.
PAUL: Okay, so… anybody who works in signal processing, in signal processing also, the term jitter comes into the picture.
PAUL: As well as in, computer vision, the term with respect to noise refers to jitter.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, with respect to our noise sensitivity, so the first thing, let's start about the working, because what it will measure, it will measure the noise.
PAUL: Okay? Now, from where that noise will come.
PAUL: Okay? Generally, most of the noise comes from the retrieve context. Because of that, there will be error in your final ads.
PAUL: Okay? And because of this, okay, the rack system will always get confused by norms.
PAUL: So, that's why to remove noise, we have to do a very good data parsing operation. Okay, because during data parsing also, you get a lot of noise. If you are not injecting or feeding clean data into your vector database, it can create a problem.
PAUL: So, that's why. So, the main generation of noise, I always feel it comes from data bars.
PAUL: Okay, so it really happens. So, that's why, like, one level that I'm telling, but actually, in this particular metric, it's much more about the retrib context. It means that there is some amount of irrelevant information in your RC, which is basically the retrip context for now.
PAUL: So, in simple terms, the working part. Now, noise sensitivity, level, which level it is?
PAUL: People are telling LLM level, retrieval level, okay, so… The idea is generation.
PAUL: Okay? Now, let's focus on the working part.
PAUL: So, the first step that you have to do, okay, so you have to do a comparison between your generated answer and the reference answer. Okay, so referencing, we always take a reference to do a validation. So, for now, because two things that I'm taking into account, so compare.
PAUL: the reference… Answer… width… generated.
PAUL: answer. Okay, it means that, so right now, the reference that you have, so this is the actual, the GT that you can think about, the actual reference, the actual information. Okay, but the generated answer is basically the response.
PAUL: From the LLM, so you have to do the comparison. Like, you have to compare the generated answer with the reference answer, as simple as that.
PAUL: Okay? So once the comparison is done, the next step is basically to identify the incorrect claims in the response.
PAUL: Identify.
PAUL: Incorrect or unsupported claims.
PAUL: Okay? In the… response.
PAUL: I hope everybody understood what is the difference between
PAUL: Reference and generated answer. Generated comes from the LLM, okay? But actually here, reference is actually, you can think about the truth that you have.
PAUL: Okay, so now comes your third one.
PAUL: Reference answer is from no. Reference answer is not from context. Reference is the actual answer that the LLM should be responding, but probably the LLM is responding something wrong, so that's why.
PAUL: No, Arian Gupta.
PAUL: 1 minus recall, you cannot do directly. Okay, 1 minus the recall, okay. Let's see if we can deduct that here by your… okay. I don't feel that, but let's see.
PAUL: identify incorrect claims in the response, that we have to do. Second, we have to do, alerts.
PAUL: Do the calculation or determine if the correct claims came from irrelevant retrieve chunks.
PAUL: game.
PAUL: from… irrelevant.
PAUL: Retrieved.
PAUL: chunks.
PAUL: Now, most of the time, this is the case that happens.
PAUL: Okay, sorry, here I have written… Correct, okay.
PAUL: The idea is to, that you will be doing the calculation that if incorrect.
PAUL: claims came from interval chunks, okay, or basically from the RCM formation. And finally, once you have done the calculation, then you will perform a scoring mechanism, okay, in your schools.
PAUL: incorrect claims from the NOIL divided by the total number of claims.
PAUL: Incorrect.
PAUL: Claims?
PAUL: Okay, from noise, or basically the unwanted data which is causing this one, or irrelevant noise, it means that irrelevant for now. Okay, you have to understand. This irrelevant term, I am using it as noise for now.
PAUL: Okay, now divided by the total claims that we have.
PAUL: And based on that, like, whatever the output that we'll be getting, okay, so…
PAUL: Now, let's do the calculation for this particular implementation.
PAUL: Alright, so let me stop sharing, and let's get back, to our… Okay, all right here.
PAUL: screens, this is desktop 2 ship.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: So, right now, the example that we have taken, okay, so… Right now.
PAUL: the question that I have asked, okay, the idea is that every option that we are doing, this is very specific, so everywhere I have added that noise, noise term.
PAUL: Okay, so the noise question, so the question, or basically the query, what is LIC known for?
PAUL: Okay, then the response we have, LIC is the largest insurance company in India, known for its vast portfolio. LIC contributes to financial stability. Okay, so this is the noise response, okay? Noise response means
PAUL: which the LLM has thrown.
PAUL: Okay, now comes your actual noise reference, which is the actual reference. So, LIC is the largest insurance company in India, established in 1956. It's known for managing a large portfolio of investments.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Just check what is the response and what is the reference. Reference is the actual information that we are looking for, and response is the one which is generated by Ellen, okay? So now, let's see, okay, what are the context that was retrieved
PAUL: So, directly, I can say here, with respect to the noise context, I can say, okay, so this context came from… so, LIC was established in 1956, following nationalization, all right, relevant, I can say, somewhere around 1956 came.
PAUL: Eli says the largest insurance company with huge investments. Alright, fine.
PAUL: LIC manages substantial funds for financial stability. Okay, again, relevant find. Then comes the Indian economy as one of the fastest growing economies.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this particular thing, which has been marked as for now, noise, in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, so this… I hope everybody understands what is the question, what is the response, what is the reference.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Please let me know, everyone.
PAUL: Is this part clear? I think for everyone, it should be clear.
PAUL: Okay, now in the next step, the idea is to analyze the claims in the response that we have.
PAUL: Okay, so if you look in the, response, okay? So, LIC is this one, and based on that, I feel that 3 main core parts are there. Okay, so response claims, very specifically.
PAUL: Analyzing the claim… okay, so analyzing the claim in response, okay, so LIC is the largest insurance company in India. Okay, true, and based on that. Okay, so right now, you can think about, I'm creating, and later on, I'll be passing this for verification.
PAUL: Eli is the largest insurance company in India. Yes, this is actually true. Matches the reference, I can say. Elise is known for its vast portfolio. Again, this part is true, matches the reference portfolio.
PAUL: LIC contributes to financial stability. Okay, but, actually, if you look here.
PAUL: Okay, LIC manages substantial funds for financial stability, and LIC contributes.
PAUL: So, right here, this particular term that we are actually keeping it as false for now.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: not in reference, possible hallucination from noise. Okay, now, really, if you think about how many of you think that, yes, this part is correct with respect to, like, LIC contributes to financial stability?
PAUL: And LIC manages substantial funds for substantial stability. Oh, sorry, financial stability. Do you think that these two sentences have the same English meaning? Yes or no?
PAUL: LIC contributes to financial stability. Now the question comes financial stability of what?
PAUL: It can be of a person, it can be of a country, it can be of a state.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And here, if you actually look into this, AIC manages substantial funds for financial stability. So here, this part is much more, because actually, there are different types of fund programs that come from LIC.
PAUL: Okay, this is much more relevant.
PAUL: Again, this is totally the one that is totally out of the context.
PAUL: So that's why I've tagged it as a false for now, within the response claims, very specifically. Okay, and let's try to do a simple, claim analysis.
PAUL: Okay? So right now, based on the claim analysis that we have done, okay, so two things are correct, only the one that I have taken into account, which is not correct.
PAUL: Okay? Partially true that I will not take into account. The idea is that to get that exact information.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, see, this part is hard-coded. If you feel at any point of time, you can take this particular example.
PAUL: Okay. But I feel that, this should be from the actual response.
PAUL: Okay, and this is there in the response. So, actually, I cannot take that Indian economy is growing, because it pass off retrieve context, okay? But if you think about, if you can put it there in the response, then in that way also, you can bring false into the system. The idea is to show you the calculation. That's why I've taken 1 for false now.
PAUL: Okay, so matches the reference, matches the reference, yes, the portfolio, vast portfolio, at least few key terms are matching here. Okay, and here, with respect to LIC contributes to financial stability, okay, not in reference, possible. Hallucination that I have kept it.
PAUL: Now, calculate the noise sensitivity. So, first of all, the total claims.
PAUL: Okay, length of the responsible, so 3 claims were made, out of which 2 were correct. 1 was unsupported, or incorrect in simple terms. So, 1 divided by 3. What will be the score?
PAUL: Quickly tell me.
PAUL: 1 divided by 3.
PAUL: Okay, so 0.33. So, based on that, we are getting this final score, okay? So, here also.
PAUL: If I try to parse the same question with the retrieve context, okay? So, let's see.
PAUL: Noise sensitivity is similar to precision, no.
PAUL: Every metric has its own uniqueness.
PAUL: Okay, because here also, I feel the numbers should be different.
PAUL: This is the only metric that we have discussed, like, lower is always better, always remember.
PAUL: Do 1 minus recall. Calculate context rescission and RE, and do it manually.
PAUL: Because right now, we are not using even the same data also, are you?
PAUL: Yeah, so I cannot say noise sensitivity is equal to 1 minus recall.
PAUL: Okay, so the data has changed. Here, LIC, there it was different, that's why. You try, take in collab, and try to do that.
PAUL: Okay, so somewhere around Radha's noise calculation score 0.33.
PAUL: Remember, lower is the better. Okay, so here you can see that it's at least clues.
PAUL: Okay? I hope everybody got an idea. The idea was to do a mimicking so that it becomes easier, as per your request.
PAUL: Okay, so based on that, we have done it, okay? Now, I'll be concluding the session, it's 12.35 already.
PAUL: And, see, now this is the entire thing that I've put together, where you can… because this part, I feel that… see, a few other things, I have kept it, if you want quickly, I can go through this, but the idea is that you guys should be going through this part.
PAUL: Okay, do you want me to quickly go through this?
PAUL: A recap, now I want to be doing a recap, okay? Recap initially in the starting of the class video.
PAUL: complete evaluation of all the six metrics. The idea is to initialize all the metrics in one shot, and then let's try to do. So here, based on that, okay, a sample, a comprehensive sample that I have taken into account, but again, this is also small.
PAUL: Okay? Then, all… I'm printing out everything, yes, so… printing out all the things that I have, total 4 chunks, reference, response, question. Now, see, in one shot, so generally, you will be seeing I'll be doing this most of the time. I will be doing the initialization, and then directly I will say that, okay.
PAUL: I want, the RAGAS to be running on top of the data.
PAUL: Okay, because actually, if I show you Notebook 10, okay, if you go to a Notebook 10,
PAUL: Hmm… okay, so with respect to… so here, a big document that I manually created.
PAUL: Basic RAT pipeline.
PAUL: If I show you, actually, with respect to bigger data, what will happen, Okay, so we share…
PAUL: So this is an evaluation set that we have created.
PAUL: Alright, few initialization wrappers, okay, fine. Say.
PAUL: Only one line. This is the line that you have to execute in Ragas, and everything will be done.
PAUL: Okay, so very, very small. You just need to create an evaluation data set. So, because of that, so this eval data set that comes into the picture. Okay, then metrics. Okay, now, if you ask me how an eval data set, probably on Wednesday, I think, I would take an extra class probably on Thursday, then let me plan
PAUL: For that, because next week, I will be starting with data bars, okay?
PAUL: Now, somewhere, can you see? Like, user input, retrieve context, response, and reference.
PAUL: This is my evaluation set, exactly how it looks like. So, pretty much a big one that I've created for now, based on the input data that I had.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, network 10, then probably we should be discussing in that field.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, you can see, when we are running actually all the 6 metrics, it will take some time.
PAUL: Wednesday extra class, I cannot take it, because Wednesday I have an extra class for the Ultimate Data Science Batch.
PAUL: Okay, I have to take it on Tuesday or Thursday. If you want, I can simply raise a poll. Based on that, I can take that.
PAUL: He told me at night, fortunately.
PAUL: Okay, because… just wait, okay, so…
PAUL: Right now, see, directly I passed this calculation, and based on that, I'm getting. So, faithfulness, answer, relevancy, context precision, context recall, so everything that we have calculated in one shot.
PAUL: Okay, then comes your final summary. Okay, now see, these are a few things that I have taken into account. Like, this is a batch of samples. So, generally, what happens when you are working with RAGAS, so when you try to combine multiple samples, it becomes a batch.
PAUL: Just like the concept in deep learning as well in machine learning. So, see, this is one sample, this is one sample, this is one sample. So, test samples, this, we can refer it as a batch.
PAUL: And then we… we have to create an evaluation dataset, as per RAGAS. So, as you can see here… Okay, so once I've created it, then I can pass it as a batch. So, this particular implementation also, I've kept it, but again, I'll be talking about this implementation in Notebook 10 very specifically.
PAUL: Okay, so for now, if you want, you can go through this stuff, but later on, again, we'll be going through, it's not like that.
PAUL: Because when I create content, I make it very fast.
PAUL: And I feel that it might be important for someone and might not be important.
PAUL: But again, like, let me just raise a poll in that case.
PAUL: Okay, so you guys can let me know with respect to…
PAUL: Okay, so should I go for twiste?
PAUL: Okay? Or, should I go for…
PAUL: First truck class, okay, so probably 9 to 11 p.m.
PAUL: Okay, so these are my options to using. If anybody's missing, they can actually go through the recording, because otherwise, because this is something extra that we have added from my side. So, the idea is to take an extra class, okay, and go through that.
PAUL: Required, okay, fun title.
PAUL: I know a few people might be missing the class, it's fine, later on, you can go through the recordings.
PAUL: It won't be a 4-hour class, okay? Close to 90 minutes.
PAUL: That is the idea.
PAUL: Okay, so I'm just raising the polls, so please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, extra class launch. Okay, you guys can let me know in the chat.
PAUL: I'll be back in 2 minutes. In the meantime, everybody please do the poll, okay? And then I will start with the next phase.
PAUL: Everyone. Okay, I'll be back in 2 minutes. Please complete this form.
PAUL: Okay, in the polls, I got close to 142. What about others? 50 people. Please do respond to the poll.
PAUL: Okay, then again, I have to, pick up the rating pool. Okay, so please…
PAUL: Don't drop, at least wait.
PAUL: When do you start it another class? When do you start it another class? From last week, I have started, Jonas. So my Wednesday is booked.
PAUL: I have slots on Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, Friday.
PAUL: Yeah, Shogandar Singh, I got your question. You don't need to paste straight. You are asking, it is possible to create a dynamic and intelligent system that automatically decides whether to directly call a LLM or to include a retrieval…
PAUL: Component… yes, we can do that.
PAUL: There is no new, this is just an extra class for now.
PAUL: Alright, so I will just share the poll results now, I'll be closing the poll. Okay, so majorly, I feel that, 92 people Thursday, 53 people on Tuesday, so we'll be going on Thursday.
PAUL: Okay, so I will just share the results with everyone, just, look, okay? The idea is to keep the transparency, it's totally based on majority.
PAUL: Okay, so it will be on Thursday, 9 to 11.
PAUL: We'll be getting the mails, probably on Wednesday, on that.
PAUL: I know a few people, if you're working, yes, it will be on ISQ only.
PAUL: If you are working fine, Cherie, later on you can go through the recording.
PAUL: Because from later phases, next week, our agenda will be data parsers, very specifically.
PAUL: Romani, it is the ultimate data science batch I have on Wednesday, that's why.
PAUL: All right, okay, now I will be raising, okay, the main poll with respect to rating. Okay, so let me launch that. Okay, so now this is the other poll. Everyone, please go through.
PAUL: Because we work hard with respect to creating the content, okay, so it's important for your feedback.
PAUL: And from your feedback, I get to know, like, exactly what are the things or the problems that we are facing. So everybody, please complete the poll, take 2 minutes, okay, and then I will start taking the doubt questions.
PAUL: No kidding. It's an old one. It started 8 to 9 months back.
PAUL: Because a lot of things are there to discuss, even which is not mentioned in your syllabus.
PAUL: Okay, so I know that if I try to take those things into account, yes, it will take more time.
PAUL: But fine. At the end of the day, I can push myself for the idea is that at least you guys can push from your site.
PAUL: Hmm… Thursday.
PAUL: Thursday, 9 to 11.
PAUL: It's just because of the extra topic of LLM as a judge, which is not included in your syllabus, but let's cover that also.
PAUL: And later on, I'll be discussing LLM as a jury. Okay, that particular concept also I'll be discussing.
PAUL: Right here, Thursday. Yonos is asking, evaluation and testing is end-to-end. What is end-to-end? What do you mean by end-to-end?
PAUL: Alright, people with questions, you can start raising your hands.
PAUL: Okay, so one by one… I will start unmuting.
PAUL: Okay, just tweet.
PAUL: A few people have raised, okay? Now, I'll be closing the poll, okay? So, let's…
PAUL: Now, start taking the doubts.
PAUL: I think there is Mitesh, Ram Prakash.
PAUL: Okay, then I have Sinivas Rajab Karna. You guys, guys, you can raise your hand and let me know the chat. I will put you in priority.
Srinivas: Hi Paul, this is Amar.
PAUL: Hmm, before it.
Srinivas: So basically, I changed the statement, from, instead of…
Srinivas: establishing the… instead of statement, like, established in 1956, I kept as not established in 1956. But still, it says relevance. Is that context correct, or since it is in the same context, it is giving tick mark in the trace… in the print?
PAUL: Mmm, probably. Just show me exactly.
Srinivas: Yeah, sure.
PAUL: Shit.
PAUL: Because exactly what is the change? Let me see.
Srinivas: Yeah, let me open, I, yeah, sure,
Srinivas: Are you able to view my screen?
PAUL: Mmm, yes.
Srinivas: Yeah. So, what I'm trying to say is, This… 1956, concerning.
PAUL: Already tested, there is a combination, yes.
PAUL: combination of all the metrics, that is in Notebook 10, where I'll be calling everything in one shot.
Srinivas: Oh, okay, so, yeah, yeah, so… Notebook 11, right?
Srinivas: Yeah.
PAUL: Right now, we discussed 12.
Srinivas: Yeah, 21.
Srinivas: So, here, when I change the statement.
Srinivas: I think we are in the seventh noise, yeah, exactly.
Srinivas: So here, right, established… initially, given the print statement as, relevance, right? Suppose even though if I keep ABC, which is not there, or even if I keep, not established in 1956, still it says, same… is it correct behavior, or, I'm just…
PAUL: Actually, see, it, it means that the embedding is matching.
PAUL: Okay. Because of that. Okay.
PAUL: Because, see, at the end of the day, the embedding, because of not, it won't be very, very far.
PAUL: Because of that, it happens.
Srinivas: Okay, to only understand the context, because earlier, when you explained, the entity is one of the value is LIC, or 1956, when it was built like that, right? Since it is matching that, it is just giving,
PAUL: Yes, because just by changing one word, I cannot say that the entire thing has changed. Though the context has changed, but really, with respect to embeddings, it's all about the numbers at the end of the day.
Srinivas: That… will that cause any…
PAUL: That is pretty much close. I can say in the high-dimensional phase, those things are close. That's why for now it's close.
Srinivas: But will that cause any meaning, especially to handle when we implement real products?
PAUL: Yeah, see, right now, I have done the hard coding. In real-world scenarios, it will be different. So when I actually take a bigger set, then you will understand recently what happened.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, the data manipulation, if you want to test it by changing your own soul data, yes, there will be a fall at any point of time. But few things I have hard-coded because of that, it is happening. And right now, based on the embedding, it is doing that particular calculation.
Srinivas: I mean, one last question is, my main question is, if I queue like this, changing naught or some value, if we implement a LLM model, will that be… it all… will that be still correct behavior, or will it give a wrong behavior for the organization? That's why I'm… I'm asking.
PAUL: See, generally, like, really, if you pass ABD, okay, then probably .inc or .privateLimited, something like that, if you pass, it becomes easier for the LLM to understand whether it's an entity or not.
Srinivas: Oh.
PAUL: Only passing A, B, D, it becomes a problem.
PAUL: Potentially.
PAUL: Okay.
Srinivas: Yeah, okay. Because I passed as LICI, LIC 123 also, it gives… it gives me same answers, that's why.
PAUL: Because that it understands, but when you pass something ABD, really, that company, that's why it's better in that way to very specifically mention, and then try.
Srinivas: Okay, yeah, thank you.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Rahul is there, okay. Mitesh, who is there, Matesh?
PAUL: Yes, I'm helping out, I think. Yes, Raul also, I've done. Yes, Matesh.
PAUL: Yep.
Mitesh Shah: So, respect to noise sensitivity, we have four parameters, specifically. Noise question, response, reference, and context, right? I'm sorry, I might be asking a very naive question, but noise reference is something which we will configure and ask the… this parameter bit to be judged on, right?
PAUL: Yes, that is the actual duty, the source truth.
Mitesh Shah: source, that's… we are going to establish that, right? That would be
Mitesh Shah: that we are going to… that's a kind of a benchmark that we are going to set for that question.
PAUL: Yes, it means that the idea is that this should be the LLM response. That's why that is the reference.
Mitesh Shah: Got it. And, regarding the earlier lectures, right, I have one important question.
Mitesh Shah: When we talk about metadata, right, we talked about for multiple vector databases, the filter context on metadata, right? Do we have any kind of methods from the documents or a database we can derive a metadata?
Mitesh Shah: Was this in production?
PAUL: You can create… there are multiple ways of creating the metadata. One is a manual process, using LLMs also you can create it. That is a costlier approach. But yes, like, during, I think, in our project, we'll be creating a rich variant metadata.
PAUL: Okay, but yes, you have to create your own metadata. Very, very good. The more rich and more vibrant it is, it becomes much easier for you.
PAUL: at any point of time with respect to retrieval, by making some conditions, as I have told you, like, if you are… if you have multiple collections, based on that, you can initialize multiple retrievers. Based on that, multiple retrievers, you can initialize multiple filter conditions. For example, just look into the HR department, finance department. In that way, you can always do that.
PAUL: So that's why somehow, like, in a single index level also, you can do it, I feel, because at the end of the day, you don't need to change the index. Rather than directly apply your filter on top of your metadata, your search becomes much more optimized, rather than looking into all, everything.
PAUL: So I feel that, yes, it's very, very important.
PAUL: Metadata we'll be talking about going forward much more.
Mitesh Shah: And if you can share some documents on it, that would be good. I am in the middle of some implementation, and I'm scared because I have 1,200 tables, and I'm… if I start manually tagging my data, I would go crazy.
PAUL: Because, again, little bit I have to look into, little bit of sample data, if you can share, based on that.
PAUL: Because in my case, that's why, like, little bit I need to look into the data, at least whatever the information of the attributes that I can extract based on the…
Mitesh Shah: company database. So, Paul, it's a full company database, including your… all the departments.
Mitesh Shah: Each and every source of truth of company is there.
PAUL: Alright.
Mitesh Shah: I'll drop an email for you. Let's connect offline in that case. I don't want to waste everybody's time here. Just last one, since we were discussing on collection, right, for a quadrant or, let's say, a simple vector database, when we say collection, right, is it… can I compare it directly as it's a kind of a schema within a database of ISQL?
PAUL: Yes, it's, schema, pretty much correct, based on that schema.
PAUL: If you remember, in the last class, we talked about vector params, very specifically in pattern, where you used to define that, this is the dimension. Okay, so yes, you can think about a schema, but rather than… it means that at every point of time, do you know about collection in MongoDB?
PAUL: The same thing, which means that you can create multiple collections.
PAUL: Okay, so based on the schema that you were defining.
Mitesh Shah: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, because the concept of collection is exactly the same in MongoDB, that's why this… in quadrant, it's called a collection, but in some other places, due to that gen AI part, people call it an index.
PAUL: But at the end of the day, both of the things refers to the same stuff.
Mitesh Shah: Okay. While generating the data, right, or while actually doing a chunking and everything, right? And when we are passing it and storing it in a particular, let's say, Collection 1, and while retrieving it through LLM, if we pass…
PAUL: No, no, no, see, there is no retrieval using NLM.
PAUL: Retriever is done through your vector DB.
Mitesh Shah: My bad. It's not retrieval. When I'm asking a question to L&M, I'm passing a context to L&M. While doing that, when we try to retrieve relevant chunks from that collection, and if I pass a wrong collection ID,
Mitesh Shah: assume, Michael.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes. It will be problematic. Yes, yes, for sure. It has to be an issue.
Mitesh Shah: Got it.
Mitesh Shah: Thank you.
Rajat Khanna: Hi, Paul.
PAUL: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, my, first question is related to retrieval part. So while the retrieval part, you were saying the indexing of chunking, as in, 0, 1, 2, 3, and it, our, resulted.
PAUL: During the retrieval part, there is no indexing.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: That is the data ingestion phase, where you perform indexing. Once the indexing is done, then you apply the retribut.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, got it, got it. And, like, as you told, like, when the indexing is done, so based on the different chunks, if the indexings are different, so result will be different, so, I'm… can you please…
PAUL: What you mean by indexing is different?
Rajat Khanna: Indexing… note in indexing, that in the face that you were saying, 0, 1, 2, 3, so as in top, top results, so.
PAUL: E as top K when I'm talking about, so the idea means that from there, what are the top 4 chunks? That I was telling you, let's take chunk, the first chunk as 0, the second chunk as 1, second chunk as 2 in that way.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and you were saying, like, if, those chunks, changes, like, whatsoever should be in the third place, if it come in the first place, then the, response will be changed. I did not get clarity on, on, on that part.
PAUL: it means that, generally, what happens if your top 4K chunks are there? Okay. Now, the idea is to look into those information, and based on that, it will throw you. Now, just think about, the result of the top 4 chunks are relevant. Then, for sure, your LLM response will be bad, nothing that you can do.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay. And in the meantime, while in the class, I asked about if
Rajat Khanna: The, information that you were saying, ground check, or, ground, information that is there that we, compare our response to.
Rajat Khanna: So, I was asking, like, if everything is hypothetical, as I asked about if we have given some information on the UFO or alien, so there is no practical proof, that we have given to it. So, how those, all the hypothetical.
PAUL: You have to create an evaluation set by yourself.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: Why you will add UFO in your data set? No, no, no, no. Think about that.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, no, it's, it's like, means we, there are,
PAUL: You won't be adding anything hypothetical. See, it's not about adding any hypothetical stuff. You create your own dataset because of that. That's why I showed you the dataset new in class.
Rajat Khanna: Yes. How it exactly looks like. Yes.
PAUL: You have to create your own dataset, then only you can do the evaluation, because that's why I've taken some hard-coded examples.
Rajat Khanna: Got it.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, see, people are telling me, take a PDF, take a PDF. But who will create the evaluation data set for that?
Rajat Khanna: Yes, yes, so that is… that is my…
PAUL: That's the main thing, like, that's why many of you don't think about take a PDF, take a PDF. Taking a PDF is easy, but I have to create an evaluation set at the end of the day. So that part we will do. So that's why, simply, I have not taken a PDF. In majorly all of my examples, I'll be keeping the document hard-coded.
PAUL: Yes, yes. Because that is a manual task, because again, to create a dataset is a really tough task.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, yeah, yeah, that was my third question, like, if we have given, 200 to 500,
Rajat Khanna: Word document or a PDF document. So then, making a comparison, like, if this is a relative information, what kind of questions that we should have. So we should… means the person should go through the document, then only that evaluation he can do.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, correct.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so it might be…
PAUL: SMEs comes into the picture, the subject matter expert.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, okay, got it. It means if we are, for example, like, in normally, we are asking questions to GPT, so if there are some persons who are also evaluating, particular information, like daily news that has been added to it.
Rajat Khanna: So there will be a person who will be evaluating whatever the daily news that has been entered into the system, and they should be doing some manual checks on that.
PAUL: You can think, but actually, with respect to daily news, rather than, like, ChatGPT will call some type of tool to do a web search, and based on that, it will show you the result.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. Actually, it happens in real time in that way.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, or a specific organization purpose, if there is a chatbot related to HR, so all the HR-related documents are uploaded to that, so there will be a person who will be verifying whatever the response that is be generated based on those.
PAUL: ESC, actually, when you are building a system, the first thing, once you have built it, you will do the evaluation. To do the evaluation, you need to build the system. Once you have done the evaluation, you can deploy it.
Rajat Khanna: Oh, okay.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so at least one time, because later on, in real time, when the user is passing the query and getting the result, that becomes your evaluation set apart, that you can use it.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. In real time, actually, the evaluation sets keep on growing, because from real-time predictions, also, you can create the evaluation set.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so it means all these, AI-related technologies, there are still a touch of manual, improvements.
PAUL: See, few things are there where human comes into the picture. I cannot say 100% everything. You sleep, everything is going on. It's not like an ETL pipeline built in data engineering. Okay, okay.
PAUL: So, like, here, things are changing. The idea is that your system will raise flags. It means that it will say that with respect to time, probably, generally what happens in machine learning. With respect to time, your model degrades.
Rajat Khanna: And we'll let the model drip take place?
PAUL: So because of that, now you know that, okay, it's time to retrain with your new data.
PAUL: So, very similarly, but here, that doesn't happen. That drifting part really doesn't happen. Rather than, you can use much better evaluations, okay, to make your rack much more robust.
PAUL: Because there are a lot of things, data parsing, each component, to make it optimized, it really takes a lot of time.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, my last question is, for example, we have a,
Rajat Khanna: internal application, like in Cisco. So, we are selling routers and everything. So, while in a front-end application, we will be calling an API, and whatsoever recently product that has been sold, that will be retrieved. For example, like, we have created a chatbot.
Rajat Khanna: So, there will be a data cutoff state will be there, so it will be, like, past one week information will be there, and yesterday's information will not be there. Is there any way, like, day-to-day information will be there in our LLM?
Rajat Khanna: Or, or a rag.
PAUL: Day to day-wise. Day to day.
PAUL: really, like, you can create a set and you can pass it to the LLM.
PAUL: Okay, that is possible, but rather than… because, see, the idea is passed to the element means, what do you mean? Do you want to change the actual weights and biases?
PAUL: No, no, because it's a daily task that I feel worth doing.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, for example, while we create… make an API call, it will be whatsoever that has been entered in the DB, it will be showing us to… showing us to us with the help of an API. But in creating an application, there will be a data cutoff point, like, past one week information will be there, but yesterday's information will not be there.
PAUL: Okay, so very specifically, like, when you are interacting with the chatbot, okay, so based on the query that you are passing it throughout the product, behind the scenes, just be sure, internally, like, through a prompt or somewhere that particular date today, what is the current date, through a Python logic implementer. Now, based on that only, it will get that information.
PAUL: That is a backend thing, you can manipulate.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, so, like, chunking that we do, like, embedding and chunking that we do, we store all the information in the, our vector DB. So, like, there is a cut-off date, like, you can say.
Rajat Khanna: 25th of November, all the information is there, but I want 29th information also should be there in our vector DB. So, for 29th information, you will be doing that data ingestion phase?
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: Yes, yes. No, yes, and how it will know.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, yes.
PAUL: Once you have done the data ingestion, then based on that, so you can add, like, current date, latest date in the backend, those logics that you can apply.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so means our vector DB will be always be, like, cut-off date, like, for example, 11 PM, it will, whatever, whatsoever has happened in the current date, all the information will be moved to VectorDB.
PAUL: all the information, okay, like, it's just like a cron job. That, probably, in a quick set, that you can do it.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, that's it. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, Moda, sir, okay, I will unmute. So, Rahul, you can also go ahead.
Ramprakash: All I'm here.
Rahul Parihar: So my question, Paul, is about…
PAUL: US guys, go first. Whoever is there from U.S. Yeah. Okay, anybody else from U.S?
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, I'll go. Recall versus, precision. So, if our system successfully retrieves the correct document…
Rahul Parihar: But place it in the position of, say, 10th value out of 10th.
Rahul Parihar: How will that impact the context precision compared to the context recall? Like, they are two different…
PAUL: all about is fetching the context, really. Now, depends upon the top-tier parameters that you are passing.
PAUL: Okay, now, with respect to that chunk, the idea is that generally the number is not 2 and 3. In real production, we increase that number to, like, 2050. So, most of the times, we always get the context.
PAUL: Okay, it doesn't happen in such scenarios that the context might be missing. But with respect to precision, it's more about the ranking of the chunk.
PAUL: So I always give much more priority towards the precision, rather than, sorry, towards the recall, rather than precision.
Rahul Parihar: recall, right? So recall would be higher with the item found, but the precision will be low with bad ranking. Is that correct statement?
PAUL: Yes, see, like, you can improve your precision by applying a re-ranking model.
PAUL: At any point of time. There is a solution. But can I say that directly you can increase the value of recall?
Rahul Parihar: Hmm.
PAUL: Working on recall is much harder as working on recession. That's why I feel that recall is much an important metric as compared to precision.
Rahul Parihar: So then, why the context precision is critical for any LLM performance, considering.
PAUL: the idea?
PAUL: on the generation. If your precision is higher, the generation results will be better.
Rahul Parihar: And what will happen to the score if,
Rahul Parihar: If the very first retrieval chunk is irrelevant, say, relevance is zero…
PAUL: If it is irrelevant, okay, first of all, why it will be zero, then it will come in top K. It cannot be never 0.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
PAUL: That's a common thing. Simple logic.
PAUL: Is there any retrieval? See, zero means no similarity. It means that the retriever has failed, nothing it has shown. Then why it will show you that?
PAUL: So that's why what happens, Rahul, when we are applying a retrieval technique, we always, first of all, give the priority, first of all, only throw me this, based on a certain, like, a threshold. It means that I only need the sum who are passing this particular threshold of distance.
Rahul Parihar: Hmm, got it, okay.
Rahul Parihar: So, I'm facing one implementation issue with, with Raka's, the next async.apply function loop is not getting call, it's giving me a runtime error.
Rahul Parihar: Mostly, that's.
PAUL: then, because that is an ASIC implementation, if you don't want, simply skip it. Not necessary.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
PAUL: Because there's not actually…
PAUL: Otherwise, see, generally, I work with scripts much more. In scripts, it works fine, but in notebooks, I have seen some issues with respect to async.
PAUL: So, that's why, even in other programming languages also, I've faced it. Very specific to Jupyter Notebook kernels. Like, in Julia also, I've faced it, okay? So, I feel that, yes, there is the issue of landscape that, but it's not part of RAGAS, the actual thing that we are discussing.
Rahul Parihar: But your execution works fine, it's just some Jupyter notebooks will have issue, or…
PAUL: It depends on system to system, OS to OS. Other people are not getting very specific to you, that's why.
PAUL: Got it, okay, let me try. Because your Ragas is not impacted. That particular thing, there is no issues into it.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, I'm not getting Raga's, you know,
Rahul Parihar: I'm not able to see Rahra's, evaluation metrics values, you know, because of that function.
Rahul Parihar: That's gross.
PAUL: Try to change that entire Jupyter notebook into a script, and then try to execute.
PAUL: That is the other way of work around, at any point of time, if you want.
Rahul Parihar: So this extra Thursday class will be your debugging class? At that time I can ask you questions?
PAUL: I'll be teaching there the things that are remaining. Next week, I'll be starting with data parser, so that Notebook 10
PAUL: The direct implementation of Raja by taking a doc.
PAUL: and LLM as a search, two things that I'll be discussing. And then finally, that next part.
PAUL: Like, Saturday, I'll be starting with docklings and unstructured, very specific links.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, let me try this. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, next, Vumika.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, Paul. First of all, thank you so much for, you know, taking into consideration our request and, explaining everything in detail. It was extremely helpful.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: So, yeah, everything's pretty clear, except for, one thing, just adding on to Matish's question on noise sensitivity,
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: You have quoted something as noise reference, right? Wherein…
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: we are saying that that is the ground truth, that we are establishing, saying that, you know, like, the LLM has to generate this particular response, but.
PAUL: Credit.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, but in real-time scenario.
PAUL: It won't be like that.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: It won't be the case, right? Like, so…
PAUL: Now, I have hard-coded a lot of things, just to show you exactly the working part. Next one, like in the next class on Thursday, that very specifically, I'll be taking an entire set of bigger document. Okay, so there, directly, I'll be doing the initialization. So, there, it won't be happening such things.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, exactly. But then, even when it's trying to
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: calculate the noise sensitivity, there will be context, quantitative context and response, right? Like.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: How will it know, like.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: You know, where is that noise reference coming into picture in the calculation itself, even is the… confusion.
PAUL: Based on my evaluation set, in my evaluation set, that information will be there.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Oh, so even… for us also, we'll have to create… in our evaluation set we are going to create, we have to establish this.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: But then, LLM… Will it create its own evaluation set when it produces the.
PAUL: You have to do it.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Did you say?
PAUL: That's the part. You have to do it manually. See, I showed you the sample, see.
PAUL: This is one sample that I have created, very specifically. Can you see here, right now, what are the things that I have created in my evaluation dataset? User input, which is basically the query retrib context.
PAUL: Response and Reference.
PAUL: Now, this is a set that will be passing it to Ragas. Based on that, it will be doing the evaluation.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: So, only if we pass this would it give us noise sensitivity? Is that what you're saying?
PAUL: Yes, using this, you can calculate all the metrics, any metrics that I have defined and know.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: There is a modern thing.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, what if, you know, we…
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Of course, there… we can get the noise sensitivity without the evaluation data set itself, right, by the function caller.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: by the default, however we get the other metrics, we can get the noise sensitivity, right? In that case, if we are not passing the evaluation data set, what is the ground truth for the LLM, then?
PAUL: Ground truth for the LLM is basically the reference that you are taking. The idea is that it should be generating this.
PAUL: But response is the actual LLM output that you have.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: what if we don't pass the… every time we don't pass the reference, right? Like, when you're talking about the reference, references that will be present.
PAUL: You have to pass. Very specifically, with respect to noise sensitivity, we have to do it. There are.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Oh, we eat nuts.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: A mandatory parameter that we'll have to pass.
PAUL: See, that's why in every framework there is no noise sensitivity, it's only in Ragas. Ragas has told you have to use reference. Nothing that I can do.
PAUL: Okay, if you go to deep eval, in deep eval framework, there is noise accessibility, it's not there.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Okay, I got it. I just wanted to, like, know if that's a mandatory parameter, and…
PAUL: 8500.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: This is a must.
PAUL: The idea is, reference is an expectation, like, what you are expecting, the actual output from the LTM.
PAUL: But you know that, yes, it can go in a different direction just because, due to hallucinations.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Hmm, okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Next… Anybody can do it.
PAUL: Modasar, if we want to go, Nagapam…
Mudassar Hakim: Hey, Paul.
Mudassar Hakim: Hey Paul, good afternoon. First of all, thanks. I think today was a very fruitful, session, and thanks to Bumika for pitching in the idea of, you know, trying to break things down.
Mudassar Hakim: Well, from a query perspective, I'll just first lay down things which I am aware of, so that I can come to the queries. Precision and recall, I get it. I think it's a little intertwined, but I get the part where, on the retriever side, how my VectorDB behaves gets the data. In terms of, not bringing in irrelevant stuff.
Mudassar Hakim: where procession comes into picture, recall being… getting all the relevant things. Recall, I have a slightly bigger doubt, maybe, on the mail or some other forum, I'll have to clear it.
Mudassar Hakim: Faithfulness, now my LLM is reading things, it doesn't hallucinate. Noise sensitivity. So, my retriever gave me good things and bad things. Noise sensitivity is all about how it disregards the bad things.
Mudassar Hakim: relevancy is not something I'm able to get it, because it feels like as if it's… it's the entire thing, what… what my Ragas does.
Mudassar Hakim: I mean, the way you explained.
PAUL: Relevancy. See, relevancy, if I'm talking about, in most of the times, most of the documents will be, like, 70% relevant information, 30% irrelevant information. In real time, chunking, this happens.
PAUL: It can be never that in one shot you get the exact information. It means that probably the query which was asked, it was very, very small. Probably within a single chunk you got the answer. But if you're asking something like a complex coding assistant, okay, now this piece of code, then that piece of code, then it becomes very, very hard.
Mudassar Hakim: I mean, rather than more than the outcome in terms of how it is doing it, the way we went into individual pieces, like what precision does, what recall does, what faithfulness does, and noise sensitivity does, right? There's a certain logic, or a certain basis
Mudassar Hakim: Which we… we under… we saw in this session today. But relevance, I mean,
Mudassar Hakim: It's like a very broad way of saying that, okay, does their answer match to the question? If it is matching, then it is correct. If it is not matching, it is not correct. It's like a big layer, you know, of right and wrong, which I'm not able to get.
PAUL: idea, see, with very specifically with respect to answer relevancy. The idea is that generating those hypothetical questions.
PAUL: Okay, that is the first part.
Mudassar Hakim: That is something we need for all, right? I mean, the reference stuff that you're referring to, right? From what we generate. So there are two things, right? The reference, and the actual thing. In case of the actual thing for Retriever, it's my.
PAUL: Answer relevancy, which relevancy we are talking about? Answer relevancy is the only one thing that we have discussed. There, the first thing is, the idea is to generate question.
PAUL: Okay, from your main query.
Mudassar Hakim: Doctor.
PAUL: with respect to relevancy, so I'm talking with respect to answer relevancy.
Mudassar Hakim: I'm talking with respect to the phase of Ragas where we are looking at answer relevance.
Mudassar Hakim: What does it internally do?
PAUL: See, answer relevance tries to address that all the things that are in your question, they have been answered or not.
PAUL: In simple terms. That's why, based on the main question, whatever the response came now, based on that, we will try to generate more questions, more hypothetical questions. That's a simple example. The idea is that, is it addressing all those questions, where and what, how, how, whatever the things that comes into the picture.
Mudassar Hakim: But that's why we are doing all the things before that. For example, to address this question of yours, we are doing first faithfulness, where we are saying that, is it hallucinating or not?
PAUL: don't think about we are doing faithfulness. It's not… it's not necessary we are using faithfulness. In some use case, you might use only one metric, answer relevancy. Totally depends upon the use case.
PAUL: So don't think that perspective. If I'm doing faithfulness, that is impacting this. It's not like that. That directly, I cannot say there is a correlation with this.
Mudassar Hakim: even implying that. No, no, I'm not implying that. I'm basically saying what is the basis? When I say faithfulness, the basis of what I'm trying to understand is it is hallucinating or not, right? For example, if, for example…
PAUL: Thinking about, see, hallucinating, you are thinking. It's not necessary that it is hallucinating every time. I can say that I'm getting directly based on the GT that I have. Can I say that.
Mudassar Hakim: Sorry, can you repeat that?
PAUL: Based on the GT, I am getting the response. Based on the actual ground rule that you have in your retrib context, based on that, I'm getting the red. So, yes, there can be a condition of no hallucination.
Mudassar Hakim: Huh, but that's the point, right? We don't know, so we put it to evaluation.
Mudassar Hakim: The whole idea is that.
PAUL: Now, the question comes in relevancy. That's the same stuff, even in relevancy. The idea is that whether the question that has been asked, whether the answer is addressed or not.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, let me take an example, maybe that will help. Let's say that I'm trying to identify a pizza with a certain constituence. Okay, let's say my pizza needs to have pepperoni, mushrooms, olives, and pineapple. That's the relevant thing. But my GET generated pepperoni, mushrooms, and dragon fruit. Now, dragon fruit was something.
PAUL: GT cannot be generated. GT is your… it means that GT is your ground rule, that it is fixed.
Mudassar Hakim: The LLF, the, the, the generator, LLF case.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, huh? So that basically, it gave… it gave dragon fruit also.
Mudassar Hakim: Where it was not needed, it was relevant was only pepperoni mushrooms, and raggle fruit is not the one, it hallucinated. So that's my faithfulness area, where I can understand that, okay, it hallucinated fruit and raggle fruit. It was not part of the original response.
PAUL: Great.
Mudassar Hakim: I'm basically asking for pizza, right? And it started generating results for burger rolls. I didn't want the burgers, I just wanted pizza, right? So that's noise sensitivity.
PAUL: hallucination also.
PAUL: Hallucination also.
Mudassar Hakim: That's shock.
PAUL: Okay, and that's the case of lower precision also. Lower context precision.
Mudassar Hakim: That's the problem. It gets all mingled up. That's why I'm trying to differentiate it.
PAUL: You cannot relate directly one metric with another, you cannot directly say that there is a direct correlation. I know that if this will happen, so for sure this will happen. But directly, the impact, or the…
PAUL: How much it is impacting, it's very hard to say, because I know, yes, one metric will change, for sure the other metric will change. But directly, because if you are doing one thing, I know the other will be impacted.
Mudassar Hakim: No, no, I mean, I get the impact. I was just trying to deep dive, to figure out when tomorrow somebody questions me that, okay, my faithfulness score is low, it's not Abdutava. What does it imply to my non-technical stakeholders when I try to express them? So I'm just taking such an example and trying to generate thoughts here.
PAUL: Okay, now, see, if you try to directly… so, right now, your requirement is to derive a relationship between answer relevancy
PAUL: Faithfulness.
Mudassar Hakim: I'm not comparing them, but if my score, relevancy, goes down, right, what does the efficient.
Mudassar Hakim: You know, what is the.
PAUL: If your answer… see, simply, if your answer relevancy goes down, it can be there is some type of hallucination. With respect to noise sensitivity, I can say that, yes, the noise is towards the higher side.
Mudassar Hakim: But then, okay, but then, doesn't my faithfulness score eventually dictate that?
Mudassar Hakim: other hallucination horror, then I think, so the first trigger point would be my faithfulness score going down, right?
PAUL: It's not about first. You are thinking about… if you apply faithfulness, then it will be first. If you don't apply faithfulness.
PAUL: Okay. It's not about applying all the systems. That's why 6 metrics. I have taught you 6. In other frameworks, only 2, 3, 4 are there.
Mudassar Hakim: Gotcha. So, on what criteria should we choose? Which metric to apply? What is the criteria we should consider?
PAUL: There is no such… see, the major ones I have told you, you should always work with context precision, context record. Faithfulness, in some places is called groundness, and .
Mudassar Hakim: Noisel.
PAUL: Is that everybody will see?
Mudassar Hakim: The noise sensitivity in no other frameworks out there.
PAUL: Okay, nobody uses noise sensitivity, because from… generally, noise comes into the picture, it means that some type of hallucination goes around.
PAUL: Okay, now Ragas has very specifically defined it. Okay, so that's why, in other frameworks, you won't be getting that. So that's why I feel that four are very, very important. Then again, that, context recall, precision, answer relevancy.
PAUL: And that one, faithfulness.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, no big one level.
PAUL: Two generations ago.
Mudassar Hakim: no fixed criteria here. It's just like he… it's there, if it helps.
PAUL: Jesus.
Mudassar Hakim: It helps, it helps, it doesn't help, it doesn't help.
PAUL: It's all about the measure.
Mudassar Hakim: Like, it's just like a measure of how much your computing power exists today, if it's good enough…
PAUL: In NLP, do you always calculate ROG1, ROG 2, ROG 3, ROG 4, ROG 5, and blue 1, blue 2, blue 3?
Mudassar Hakim: You never calculate. But there is one function, using that function, you can calculate everything.
PAUL: But really, it doesn't matter to us. If ROG1, ROG 2, ROG 3, by that only, I can take a decision.
PAUL: It's about the metrics are more here, if I try to compare it with directly. I feel that, yes, this is better, somehow, as it has more number of stars with respect to implementation and taken into production.
PAUL: So, it's totally up to you which metric, but I feel that 4 you should always use. Groundness.
PAUL: Then response relevancy, the recall, and precision. And then again, like, entity recall, in other frameworks, there won't be anything related to entity recall also.
Mudassar Hakim: Chilli, Cheneya, fine. Thanks, Paul.
Mudassar Hakim: Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, Paul…
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Yeah,
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Paul, thanks for teaching the, things, and it's a really very good, effort and, good guidance, okay? We see today, Ragas, that we do have a retrieval matrix and a generator matrix with, context precession and context recall, or this kind of things, faithfulness. So, let's say if we use other than RAG, RAGAS, okay.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Is it the same kind of retrieval matrix will apply, or it would be different?
PAUL: Same only, just the port syntax, initialization, classes, those things will change.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, so the concept is same matrix, we have to use it.
PAUL: Jesus.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Sure, okay, yeah. That's all my side. Thank you.
Ramprakash: Hello, Mother.
PAUL: Thanks, Ram, Prakash.
PAUL: I'm a jam.
PAUL: You know, 3 people have 100.
Ramprakash: Yeah, yeah, I'm there.
Ramprakash: Apal can be able to hear me?
PAUL: Prakash. Yes, please.
Ramprakash: Actually, I have, three questions, okay? This is regarding, it is from, forma implementation, okay? So, we have injected, more than 100 documents.
Ramprakash: Okay, when we are retrieving the document, Okay, number one.
Ramprakash: So, see, I'm fetching the data based on a query. Okay, so, say, some kind of supplier name or something, notice.
Ramprakash: So, say, example, X1 is my supplier. I am searching with the context of X1, okay? So, it's throwing it, actually, when we are getting, and we are gauging that also, okay, by Ragas, and it is giving X11, X12, X1, all the stuff, actually, it is listing, okay? So…
Ramprakash: So, how do we improve the, accuracy of our, gauging? That, actually, we are unable to do that, number one.
PAUL: How we want to improve the accuracy of your.
Ramprakash: acne query, that context.
PAUL: No, no, what? Again, I didn't get to.
Ramprakash: say, Paul, luckily I'm sorry. No, no. You want to increase the accuracy of what? Tell me that first.
Ramprakash: Say, I'm searching some contacts, okay? Say, example, Ramadan is…
PAUL: Searching is a retrieval part.
Ramprakash: Yes, sir.
PAUL: Okay, so now pushing…
Ramprakash: So, there are three parts, actually, I have questions, okay? One, actually injecting. Injecting, I'll put it in the last. Actually, we are talking, actually, today class, actually, we are explaining about the, retrieval and, the ragas, right?
PAUL: I think I talked about retrieval today.
Ramprakash: No, no, no. The previous class and today. Today, we have discussion now one day under ragas, and right?
PAUL: Yes, it's only the metrics definition.
Ramprakash: Yes, that, actually, that gauging, when we are doing that metrics, okay, see that, actually, so,
Ramprakash: So, I'm getting around .56, 0.57, 0.62, all this stuff, okay? But my right answer is not there at all in that, okay? So, it is, how do… how do we…
PAUL: Right answer is not there where, during evaluation.
Ramprakash: Evaluations.
PAUL: Generally, see, during evaluations, you don't get answers, you just get numbers, based on the evaluation set that you have created.
Ramprakash: Yes.
PAUL: You really need to look into your evaluation set, or whoever has created it. You need to do the validation, like, how he has created, based on that, those things comes into the picture.
Ramprakash: Hmm.
Ramprakash: Okay, so my second question is, so we injected the 100-pass document, okay? If, your document, okay, say, example, any extra doc, actually, it is being revised, and it is version 1, 2, it is moving. How do we handle this? Data claim?
PAUL: You have to maintain a file version system, so based on the recent file changes, you have to create such file…
PAUL: Just like GitHub, it's a version controlling system, similarly a file version control that you need. It means that with respect to any file changes, you need to create such a system. Based on that, you can do the updates.
Ramprakash: Okay, so in the time of actually retrieval, it is actually taking from all, so where is the control out of it? See, current version is 3. Actually, it is taking the data from 2 also. Where is the control on that?
PAUL: It's taking from two different versions.
Ramprakash: Version 2 also. Version… actually, see, version 1, version 3 is the latest. Version 2, version 1 is there in the…
PAUL: The idea is, say, if you are having… if you are injecting something new, okay, the idea is that delete the old stuff. For example, if you have a version 3, then why you want to keep V2?
PAUL: If you feel if V2 is important, because then I'll be treating V2 as a totally different document, and not as V3 similar in that case. Other, simply delete the embedding from the vector database.
Ramprakash: Oh, they don't need that, the.
PAUL: Otherwise, even just duplicating data, which is a very bad practice in vector teams.
Ramprakash: Yeah.
Ramprakash: So, how do we… actually, based on the version control, how do we maintain that?
Ramprakash: Data cleared, I don't have any clue.
PAUL: That is simple software logic, nothing related to AI.
Ramprakash: Okay.
Ramprakash: So, we should know, we should know the… what is the latest session when we are actually fetching the data, right?
PAUL: No, based on time, what file is changed, where it has been appended, those are the attributes we'll be looking for. For example, in a simple TXT file, I will tell that, okay, in line number 100, there was a change. 100, 200, there was a change.
PAUL: Okay, now I have two options.
Ramprakash: One?
PAUL: completely delete my old file, okay, and take this new file, and just create the embedding. That is one option. The other one option is basically updating the embedding. Okay, so probably that line number 100, where was there in that specific chunk?
PAUL: Okay, that was changed, so that particular chunk I will go, I will delete that, then update it.
Ramprakash: There won't be… actually, there won't be any confusion there, right, while updating that embedding.
PAUL: No confusion.
PAUL: you are thinking there, but actually there is no confusion in that. It's pretty much standard forward, it's just a simple update operation.
Ramprakash: Just like you update in a normal database.
Ramprakash: That same thing only.
PAUL: Yes, but you have to own a proper file versioning system that you need.
Ramprakash: Thanks.
PAUL: Yes, Aruna, use metadata, correct. Using metadata, we can actually fetch any star.
PAUL: Next, Lakshmi.
Lakshmi: Hey, Paul.
Lakshmi: So my question is regarding, Maya's sensitivity. So, I see that, in your example, Maya's question, response, and reference, all three are clear.
Lakshmi: And, I see there is an array of noise contexts. So, in real-world scenarios, usually, like, how do we create these noise contexts, like, using a different LLM?
PAUL: will create this context from the, you think you can create it easily. See, it's actually creating evaluation data set that you have to do it yourself.
PAUL: Okay, you can use an LLM and you can tell the LLM, but really, after the LLM has done it, you really need to do a validation on top of that.
PAUL: Because that reference thing that you have, that really need to be checked by yourself. The other things, really, you cannot check, you can skip that, but I feel that that reference is really important.
Lakshmi: Yeah, if in case of very big, heavy documents, like, what's the standard that follows in the industry?
PAUL: There is always someone, okay, who will be doing a check.
Lakshmi: True to manual thing.
PAUL: Not for every HN manual, at least for one entry he'll be checking.
Lakshmi: Just, for something, okay? Yes.
PAUL: I'll go to my seat.
PAUL: If… that's the same thing. I can hire people, or I can use 10 or 15 LLMs to do that. Okay? One by one, each test case, there's 10, 15 LLMs. Like, at the end of the day, in both the places, I need to spend money on people or on LLMs.
PAUL: Because I'll be selecting the top 15 LLMs from the market, and based on that, I can do a voting, and based on that, I can take an input.
Lakshmi: Yeah, yeah, definitely. Thank you so much.
PAUL: of the day, always working with LLMs, I feel that at least somebody should be there who knows the use case, the actual subject matter expert.
PAUL: Because from a developer perspective, it becomes very hard, because really, somebody is working in healthcare and anything. The developer might have no idea. He knows working with the algorithms and other stuff, but actually what is going on? So that's why the data needs to be verified somewhere.
Lakshmi: randomly some samples to be verified.
PAUL: Yes, actually.
Lakshmi: Yeah, otherwise, it can… random, yeah, okay.
Lakshmi: Yeah, so this, today's session is very informative, so, and thank you so much for bringing everything together.
PAUL: I spent some…
Lakshmi: I'm reading, and it was… it was a little difficult for me to understand, but today it's really good, yeah. Thank you so much for this.
PAUL: Alright guys, I'll be concluding the session for today, okay? So, bye-bye everyone, thanks for joining, let's meet on Thursday.